<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Futebol Brazil</title>
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com" />
    <updated>2018-11-12T09:09:53-02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ryan O&#x27;Mullan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://futebolbrazil.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 33</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-33/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-33/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-12T09:09:42-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/18/DSC02906.JPG" alt="Itaquera - Arena Corinthians" />
                    Palmeiras’ seemingly inexorable march to the title faltered slightly on Sunday evening as they could only manage a draw away at an out-of-sorts Atletico-MG. A well worked move down the left was finished in spectacular style by Elias as he teed himself up to volley&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/18/DSC02906.JPG" alt="Itaquera - Arena Corinthians" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras’ seemingly inexorable march to the title faltered slightly on Sunday evening as they could only manage a draw away at an out-of-sorts Atletico-MG. A well worked move down the left was finished in spectacular style by Elias as he teed himself up to volley the ball into the top corner past a helpless Weverton, giving Atletico-MG the lead just under half-way through the second half. It took a good save from the Palmeiras goalkeeper to stop Luan making it two just minutes later, as he found space in the area after a give-and-go with Fabio Santos and unleashed a stinging low shot. It was Palmeiras, however, who got a rub of the green as they were awarded a soft penalty after Adilson was adjudged to have pulled back Edu Dracena in the 77th minute. Bruno Henrique duly scored a perfectly placed penalty, sending Victor the wrong way and the ball into the bottom right-hand corner, ensuring that that his team took another step towards the title. This step was made all the more comfortable by the news that in the north-east of the country Internacional were unable to capitalise on an early lead against Ceara, ending up with a 1-1 draw of their own. Leandro Damiao’s sixth goal in six games, finishing after Everson had blocked his initial shot, gave Palmeiras’ closest rivals the lead, before Ricardinho levelled matters in the 42nd minute, converting a low cross from close range. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Estadio Manoel Barradas played host to the weekend’s third derby, following Saturday’s ties, as Vitoria and Bahia played their roles in an entertaining 2-2 draw. The hosts Vitoria were twice pegged back as they went in search of a vital win and a chance to move out of the relegation zone. Bahia are much more comfortably placed in mid-table, six points above trouble, and this will certainly feel like two-points lost for Paulo Carpegiani’s struggling team. In Porto Alegre, Gremio snatched a win thanks to Matheus Henrique’s 95th minute goal. Thiago Galhardo finished off a break-away move to put Vasco in front on 12 minutes, only for Jael to equalise eight minutes later, heading in unmarked at the far post. Seventy five goalless minutes then followed until Matheus Henrique’s decisive contribution: an ambitious long range shot, which should have been dealt with easily but instead was fumbled into the net by Vasco’s Uruguayan #1, Martin Silva. Sunday’s action was rounded off by Sport Recife’s visit to Rio to meet Fluminese. Sport have enjoyed a great run of form in recent weeks, winning four of their last five, and will have arrived at the Maracana hopeful of another good result as they faced a side who have lost their last two without scoring. A goalless first half was followed by a scoreless second, however, and both teams had to settle for a point, a result which kept Sport Recife out of the bottom four, at least until Chapecoense play on Monday evening. Fluminese came closest to breaking the deadlock, and had the ball in the net late on after Luciano’s close-range finish, only for the assistant referee to flag it up as offside.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s match-ups saw derby action in both Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro as Flamengo visited Botafogo and Corinthians hosted city rivals Sao Paulo. Given their poor run of form recently, Corinthians gave a good account of themselves, holding Diego Aguirre’s team to a 1-1 draw despite going down to ten men shortly before the interval. Chilean midfielder Angelo Araos was sent-off for a second bookable offence when he hit out after a coming together with Reinaldo. In fact it was Corinthians who took the lead, Ralf on target with a low drive from distance after 72 minutes, but Sao Paulo finally made their numbers count as Brenner equalised nine minutes later, directing Nene’s goalbound shot past Cassio. Up the coast in Rio, Botafogo earned an important three points in a bad tempered 2-1 victory. Ten yellow cards were shown as goals from Erik and Leonardo Valencia earned the points for the team in black and white. Vitinho nodded in a reply for Flamengo early in the second half, but Botafogo did enough to hang on for the win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s other matches were similarly marked by ill-discipline. Both sides ended the match with ten men as already-relegated Parana visited America-MG. Parana’s Rene was the first to see red before Messias was also sent marching in the 86th minute. The match is likely to be remembered for more positive reasons however, by half of those concerned at least, as a 0-1 win for Parana ended a winless streak stretching all the way back to July. Atletico-PR and Cruzeiro went one better than the Rio derby as eleven players were booked in their encounter. Marcelo Cirino and Raphael Veiga’s first half goals were enough to secure the points for Atletico-PR, a win which lifted them into 6th place and the Libertadores qualifying round spots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday night football was provided by Chapecoense’s visit to Santos, as the away team looked to leapfrog their relegation rivals into 16th place.  </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 32</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-32/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-32/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-06T07:16:48-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/17/Screen-Shot-2018-11-06-at-07.15.48.png" alt="Palmeiras fans at Allianz Parque" />
                    Palmeiras took a huge stride towards securing the title on Saturday evening as they came out on top in an exciting 3-2 win over Santos. This looked to be a tricky tie for the leaders, with Santos on a good run of form and the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/17/Screen-Shot-2018-11-06-at-07.15.48.png" alt="Palmeiras fans at Allianz Parque" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras took a huge stride towards securing the title on Saturday evening as they came out on top in an exciting 3-2 win over Santos. This looked to be a tricky tie for the leaders, with Santos on a good run of form and the team in green still nursing a potential hangover after their midweek semi-final exit from the Copa Libertadores at the hands of Boca Juniors. If they were feeling tired after their exertions against the Argentines, they showed no sign in the first half as they went into the interval two goals to the good, courtesy of Dudu and Edu Dracena. With the game very much in their grasp, things took a turn when Jonathan Copete clawed one back for Santos on 55 minutes. Ten minutes later and it was game on as Dodo levelled for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Peixe. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The lead was not to last, however, as Vitor Luis grabbed the winning goal from a free-kick in the 71st minute. There was still time for more drama as Santos’ Diego Pituca picked up a second yellow card and was dismissed ten minutes from time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s other games were not quite so dramatic. Gremio and Vasco da Gama both winning 0-1 away at Atletico-MG and Fluminese respectively. Pedro Geromel struck early for Gremio, while Maxi Lopez’s fine run of form continued with his fifth goal in his last six games. Atletico-MG had Ecuador midfield Junior Sornoza dismissed deep into injury time to compound the loss.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sunday afternoon saw fourth host second as Sao Paulo welcomed Flamengo to the Morumbi. Like Saturday’s main attraction, this clash between two of this season’s title contenders didn’t disappoint with four goals and leads won and lost. Diego Souza opened the scoring for Sao Paulo with his eleventh goal of the season, only for the hosts to be pegged back two minutes later as Fernando Uribe netted an equaliser in the tenth minute. After the break, Helio Junio must have though he’d done enough to secure all three points for Sao Paulo, only for Rodinei to score in the 80th minute and draw the team from Rio level once again. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other big game on Saturday took place in Porto Alegre as Internacional faced Atletico-PR. A win would move the home team up to second place, but for most of the match it looked like it would be another missed opportunity for Odair Hellmann’s team as Camancho scored for Atletico-PR in the 62nd minute. Rodrigo Moledo equalised in the 82nd minute, and it looked like Internacional would have to settle for a point, but they were awarded a 94th minute penalty, which was duly converted by Andres D’Alessandro. His team are now just five points behind Palmeiras with six games left to play. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elsewhere, Parana and Vitoria played out a 1-1 draw, which did neither side any favours in their battle against the drop, but did halt a run of four successive losses for the league’s bottom side. Parana are now winless in 18 games, and Serie B bound barring a miracle involving a run of six successive wins and a serious goal difference overhaul. America-MG also remain in imminent danger of the drop as they failed to pick up any points at home to Cruzeiro, losing 1-2 on the night.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Remarkably, last season’s champions Corinthians are still not out of danger and a couple more results like Sunday evening’s loss to Botafogo may well see </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Timao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sweating over results elsewhere. Rodrigo Lindoso scored the only goal of the game for the hosts, a result which pulled Botafogo further clear of the relegation zone. Bahia condemned Chapecoense to defeat by the same scoreline, Elber getting the vital goal and helping his team to the relative comfort of 11th place while leaving Chapecoense firmly in the drop zone.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday evening, Sport Recife continued their recent renaissance with a narrow win over fellow strugglers Ceara. Gabriel scored the all important goal in the 53rd minute, helping his side to their fourth win in the last five games and, most importantly, lifting them out of the bottom four.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Away Daze</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Hardwicke</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/an-away-daze/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/an-away-daze/</id>
            <category term="Sao Paulo"/>
            <category term="Juventus"/>
            <category term="Copa Paulista"/>
            <category term="Away Days"/>

        <updated>2018-11-05T22:44:59-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/16/PHOTO-2018-11-05-13-09-35.jpg" alt="" />
                    It’s 8 am on a Sunday morning and the sun is shining brightly on the crowd outside the ‘Onion bar’ in Mooca, a barrio in the Central-West district of Sao Paulo. The Onion is home to Sector 2, a group of C.A. Juventus fans who&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/16/PHOTO-2018-11-05-13-09-35.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s 8 am on a Sunday morning and the sun is shining brightly on the crowd outside the ‘Onion bar’ in Mooca, a barrio in the Central-West district of Sao Paulo. The Onion is home to Sector 2, a group of C.A. Juventus fans who have welcomed me with open arms since I first found my way to a Juve game around a year ago. A group of around 40 or so fans have gathered here to take the two-hour bus ride North to Atibaia, a conurbation of around 125,000 people, for an important game in the Copa Paulista (a tournament for sides in the state of Sao Paulo who are not part of the national set-up).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Away games for Juventus are usually within city limits (and reachable by public transport) or several hundred kilometres away.  As a result, bus trips such as these are somewhat rare and excitement levels are high: many of the beers marked for consumption en route have already disappeared and large glasses of industrial-flavoured cachaca are doing the rounds. Everyone is in high spirits. But weren’t we supposed to be leaving already? The bus driver seems to be the only one keen to get going. Eventually, more beers and ice arrive, the big bass drum is loaded onto the bus and we are on our way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The party starts immediately and for a Sunday morning I must say it is a sight, and sound, to behold.  For the duration of the journey, the seats are treated like the terraces at Rua Javari, Juventus’ home, as the group bounce and sway through a repertoire of songs seemingly aimed at insulting every other club in Sao Paulo one after the other.  Moving slowly through the notorious city traffic, the bus is greeted with no shortage of honks, cheers and waves from passers-by. Heavy smoke fills the air, thankfully masking the smell from the toilet (passengers who force their way through the throng are urged not to flush for fear of making it worse), the drum beat pounds away and as we make our way into the countryside, light fittings and luggage racks begin to fall from the ceiling, much to the amusement of those underneath. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we approach Atibaia, I check the time on my phone and am alarmed to note that kick-off time was 15 minutes ago! I turn to inform Joao, stood next to me, but he simply beams at me as he puts his arm around my shoulder: ‘Yes we are missing the game,’ he chuckles, ‘but we knew this would happen before we left The Onion.’ It takes me a few moments to process this. I glance around at the swaying, smiling, care-free faces in front of me and am reminded of a familiar feeling I have experienced many times before in situations such as these: sure, the game is important, but there is something more powerful here, a togetherness, a bond formed by the collective expression of emotion that occurs when passionate people gather together over something they love. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel this sensation once more when, after the game, I remark to Fernando, one of the leaders of Sector 2, how well Juventus played today. “Yeah?” he replies, looking vaguely pleased with this suggestion, for he has no idea what happened on the pitch. Like others around him, his match was spent facing his fellow supporters, bouncing up and down, arms pumping rhythmically in time with the chanting. Expressing his love for the beautiful game.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Choosing Sides</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/choosing-sides/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/choosing-sides/</id>
            <category term="Corinthians"/>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>
            <category term="Bahia"/>

        <updated>2018-10-31T19:02:40-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/15/4760f175-2f20-4d09-abad-df9e82fc312e.JPG" alt="Corinthians x Bahia" />
                    I meet Claiton and his family on the underground en-route to Itaquera, the home of Corinthians and the battle ground for not only three points but the hearts and minds of some special supporters. A friend from playing football, this is our first time watching&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/15/4760f175-2f20-4d09-abad-df9e82fc312e.JPG" alt="Corinthians x Bahia" />
                <p>I meet Claiton and his family on the underground en-route to Itaquera, the home of Corinthians and the battle ground for not only three points but the hearts and minds of some special supporters. A friend from playing football, this is our first time watching a game together. When I told him that I was part of this blog and looking to write about supporters of different teams, he immediately invited me to this fixture - an example of the hospitality extended to me from everyone I was to meet. Today is Corinthians x Bahia. Maybe not a standout fixture in many households, but the game of the year for this family. Claiton relocated to Sao Paulo for work, but has kept his love of EC Bahia alive from afar or, on occasions like this, by getting to the game when they come to town. With two young sons, it provides a great chance for them to stay aware of their roots in the North-East and keep in touch with fellow internal migrants who, for one reason or another, have ended up far from home. What better way for a father to bond with his sons than a shared love of a football team? One hitch though: Mum supports Corinthians!</p>
<p>As we shoot along the red line to the brand new Arena Corinthians, Claiton breaks the bad news to me. Pedro, his eldest, will be in the home end. The boys have attended games since before they could walk. In fact, Pedro’s first match was as a three month old attending a final in Bahia. But times have changed and here we are with him heading to his first game as a Corinthians fan. I ask Mum, Jeane, if she has any fears about her son becoming a fan of a notoriously tough “team of the working people”. The answer is no. Yes, there is a bad reputation and yes, there are some bad apples but no worse than any other team. This is a fact borne out by the swathes of families I see in and around the ground. I turn to Claiton. How does he feel about his first born choosing a team other than Bahia? He’s magnanimous if still very disappointed. As far as I’m concerned it beats him joining the masses of PSG and Barcelona supporting kids that litter every playground and football field in the country.</p>
<p>And so to the game. We are joined by friends and family from both sides and make our way up the hill to the stadium. And then a twisting of the knife, as Pedro gets his first Corinthians jersey. Time comes to part ways. Jeane and Pedro go their way and myself, Claiton and Gabriel, the youngest member of the family, head towards the away end. And then it happens, an act of resistance, Claiton gets Gabriel’s Bahia top out of his bag. Gabriel’s smile is as big as Dad’s, and as we mingle with the fellow Bahia fans I can’t help but hope it stays this way. The sense of community and sharing of an experience is unlike any I’ve experienced at a Brazilian ground. Everyone is in it together and Gabriel is in the right place. Clinging to Dad, Gabriel soaks in the atmosphere, a mix of giddy excitement and awe on his face. Although a brand new stadium, the Arena Corinthians is quite open to the elements and as the drizzle becomes rain, a lady behind Claiton offers to shelter Gabriel from the elements. Again the sense of belonging, of being one of the family, shines through despite the miserable weather. A notorious venue for boisterous home fans, the game's noise and action heats up as the game goes on and it  finishes in a crescendo of goals in the final few minutes. It ends 2-1 to Corinthians and they jump ahead of Bahia in the league. However, the real result that matters is that of who the boys have chosen to support. That ends 1-1. I guess a draw is a fair result, no matter the score!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 31</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-31/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-31/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-31T18:55:24-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/14/DSC02392.JPG" alt="Morumbi Stadium" />
                    This week’s action took place over Friday, Saturday and Monday due to the Brazilian presidential election, which was held on Sunday. All eyes were on the world-renowned Maracana as the top two sides in the country, Flamengo and Palmeiras, squared up for what promised to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/14/DSC02392.JPG" alt="Morumbi Stadium" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week’s action took place over Friday, Saturday and Monday due to the Brazilian presidential election, which was held on Sunday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All eyes were on the world-renowned Maracana as the top two sides in the country, Flamengo and Palmeiras, squared up for what promised to be a potential title-decider. Flamengo needed to avoid defeat at all costs in order to keep Palmeiras within touching distance, and they were able to do that courtesy of Colombian Marlos Moreno’s equaliser after Dudu had put </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Verdao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">into a second-half lead. Flamengo remain four points behind the leaders with seven games left to play.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Friday’s matches saw an out-of-sorts Sao Paulo visit Vitoria, while in Rio de Janeiro Vasco da Gama hosted Internacional. Sao Paulo desperately needed to get their faltering season back on track with a win against the strugglers from Salvador, and they had Bruno Alves to thank for their first victory in seven games - the centre-back sweeping home a cut-back in the 36th minute. It wasn’t all good news for the team in white however, as goalkeeper Jean, who previously represented Vitoria’s city rivals Bahia, was dismissed after the final whistle for provoking the home fans, sparking angry scenes on the pitch. Internacional blew the chance to move into second place as they could only manage a draw on Friday evening. Uruguayan striker Jonatan Alvez had given them the lead in the 85th minute, only for Maximiliano Lopez to score his fourth in five games with an injury-time penalty. Internacional also had a player sent-off very late on, with Edenilson receiving his second yellow card in the 95th minute of a match beset by contentious decisions from the referee.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Saturday afternoon, Santos put Fluminese to the sword with three goals in the last six minutes of their home tie at the Estadio Urbano Caldeira. Chapecoense kept themselves in the struggle to avoid the drop by beating America-MG at home - Wellington Paulista grabbing the vital goal in the 60th minute. Corinthians were able to arrest any further decline in their standing with Danilo playing a starring role from the bench and grabbing both goals in a 2-1 victory. Cruzeiro eased to a 3-1 victory over Parana, who could be relegated at the end of Round 33, if results do not go their way. Atletico-PR’s good run of form continued with a 2-1 comeback win over Botafogo, a result which sees the Rio-based team just one point above the relegation zone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The match of the day, as far as the neutral is concerned, came at the Arena do Gremio where Sport Recife were looking to build on last week’s win against Vasco da Gama, as they seek an improbable escape from relegation. Seven goals from six different goal-scorers saw Sport throw away a two-goal lead, before regaining the advantage with Gabriel’s 53rd minute strike, only to lose it again just minutes later as Thonny Anderson equalised for Gremio. Not to be deterred, Sport kept looking for a way through, and in the 64th minute their endeavour was rewarded when Jair claimed all three points for the away side. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday evening, Ceara took on Atletico-MG and secured a vital 2-1 win to put daylight between themselves as the teams at the bottom of the table. Juninho Quixada and Leandro Carvalho got the goals that moved their side up to 13th place. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Derby Day Rio Style</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/derby-day-rio-style/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/derby-day-rio-style/</id>
            <category term="Rio"/>
            <category term="Fluminense"/>
            <category term="Flamengo"/>
            <category term="Derby"/>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-30T19:47:09-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/13/rio.jpg" alt="" />
                    The first our taxi driver notices the Flamengo strip on Matt is about 20 minutes or so of erratic driving into our trip from the Rio bus station to our hotel in Lapa. He turns around and gives the thumbs down “not good” he states&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/13/rio.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>The first our taxi driver notices the Flamengo strip on Matt is about 20 minutes or so of erratic driving into our trip from the Rio bus station to our hotel in Lapa. He turns around and gives the thumbs down “not good” he states in Portuguese to Matt who’s been in the country all of a week. To be fair to Matt he is more concerned about the driving than the gentle chastising he is getting for choosing the biggest club in Rio to support for his holiday. Next on the list for telling off is Lili. She has opted for a museum rather than the Fla-Flu classico. “But this is culture, this is more than a game, this is life” he states. Well, that’s why we are here. To sample culture. To enjoy life.</p>
<p> We finally get checked into the nearest Days Inn after our brief attempt to check into a local brothel gets noticed and the situation rescued by Lili. Things they don’t tell you on trip advisor! And so we set off to the Maracana. If Brazil is some spiritual home of sexy football then the Maracana is its temple. Home of Fluminense and the setting for two world cup finals this is the stadium in South America that we’ve all heard of since childhood. We opt to get there three hours early on the advice of our taxi driver. He seems to think that it will take that long to collect our tickets and while I’m skeptical I’m aware that there will be beer and atmosphere to be soaked in. Turns out I am right. Tickets retrieved with minimal fuss it is time to grab some cans of Brahma and take a walk around the old place. They say never meet your heroes and from the outside I’m beginning to think the same might be said of your favourite football satdiums. A ramshackle concrete bowl low set amongst the motorway flyovers and derelict buildings doesn’t inspire much hope. The atmosphere outside is cordial with fans mixing and enjoying drinks together and as the Rio sun scorches down (the first glimpse in over a week- sorry Matt) I’m beginning to think this might not be the worst way to spend a Saturday afternoon after all.</p>
<p>As my third beer goes down I get to thinking about other derbies I’ve been to. In Argentina I made the pilgrimage to Monumental to see the Superclassico, River x Boca. When lists are drawn up of the must see games in life this always seems to come up top. My experience was an amazing one, being in with the Ultras and right in the midst of the flares and tifos. However, with the lack of away fans due to previous years of violence it was missing something.What’s a rivalry without a rival? The same can be said of the Sao Paulo derbies that I have attended between Palmeiras and Sao Paulo or Corinthians respectively. Full houses and full of action but no away fans leaves a surreal feeling. Maybe I’m unusual or maybe it is my upbringing but half the fun of a derby match is having your mortal enemy within yelling distance. To be able to spout range at them for 90 minutes then meet your pals from the other side for a pint after and disagree about what you’ve just seen. This brings me to the derby I was raised on and attended numerous times. For me, the best will always be the Old Firm. Anyway, here I am in Rio, with a mix of fans and an open mind. Could this be the best? Is this life? It is time to see what this derby is made of.</p>
<p>The feeling of walking into any stadium for the first time is something special. Finding your way up the stairs, the light at the end of the tunnel, the glorious green pitch coming into sight. In this respect the Maracana doesn’t disappoint. Rejuvenated for the 2014 World Cup but not well maintained the stadium manages to mix old world charm with a comfortable viewing arena. We take our seats and watch the warm up. The stadium begins to fill and to our surprise a man selling beer comes past our seats. Having watched most of my Brazilian football in Sao Paulo’s teetotal stadiums this is a welcome surprise. My mind casts back to the stands of Parkhead and the mayhem such a scheme would cause come derby day! As more people enter we notice there is indeed an away end and a home with vocal support but unbelievably for a game of this magnitude it isn’t a sell out. The 50,000 or so that have filled into the stadium give it their best and the teams come out to fanfare and cheerleading. And here is probably as good as it gets. The game starts. Flamengo cruise to an early lead which befits their status of title challengers against their mid-table enemies. They add two more to their score sheet, each goal met with a cacophony of firecrackers. The beers keep coming as the sunsets over the Maracana. Flamengo have won and Matt is happy. As we set off to find a taxi to take us to our non-brothel hotel Matt is happy man- better than a day at the museum we agree. I wonder if our first driver of the day would still agree.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 30</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-30/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-30/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-26T15:12:17-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/11/IMG-20181022-WA0011.jpg" alt="Palmeiras x Ceara - 21/10/18" />
                    Palmeiras managed to hold on to their lead and secure all three points in Sunday’s 2-1 victory over Ceara, despite having forward Deyverson dismissed in first-half injury time for an inexplicable chest-high studs-up challenge on Richardson. A double from Bruno Henrique was enough for the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/11/IMG-20181022-WA0011.jpg" alt="Palmeiras x Ceara - 21/10/18" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras managed to hold on to their lead and secure all three points in Sunday’s 2-1 victory over Ceara, despite having forward Deyverson dismissed in first-half injury time for an inexplicable chest-high studs-up challenge on Richardson. A double from Bruno Henrique was enough for the home team, Arthur replying for Ceara in the 55th minute.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Title rivals Flamengo kept the pressure on with an impressive result away at bottom side Parana. Three second-half strikes followed Lucas Paqueta’s 19th minute opener to give </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Mengao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a comfortable trip back to Rio de Janeiro, and keep the gap at the top down to four points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s matches saw America-MG play out yet another draw, their fifth in seven games, with Gremio. The match finished 1-1 with Jean Pyerre’s penalty drawing Gremio level after Juninho scored for the hosts. Bahia took maximum points from their trip to Botafogo, courtesy of Edigar Junio’s strike just minutes after coming on as a second-half sub. Sao Paulo and Atletico-PR were unable to find a way past each other in an unremarkable game at the Morumbi stadium, which must surely spell the end of any lingering title aspirations for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Tricolor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sport Recife meanwhile earned a vital win in their attempt to avoid relegation, beating Vasco da Game 2-1 and with enough to spare to afford a 94th minute penalty miss by Gabriel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Sunday afternoon, Vitoria hosted an out-of-form Corinthians side and played their part in an entertaining 2-2 draw, with a goal apiece scored in a frantic injury-time period. Roger thought that he had secured the win for the Sao Paulo-based side with his 91st minute strike, until Neilton snatched a point for Vitoria in the 93rd minute. Fluminese beat Atletico-MG 1-0 with Luciano scoring in the 63rd minute after Fabio Santos had missed a penalty for Atletico-MG at the start of the second half. Cruzeiro had no problem dispatching Chapecoense on Sunday evening, with three first-half goals making for an easy three points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round’s last fixtures saw Internacional host Santos hoping to keep within touching distance of the top two, and Ceara and Crumeabzeiro catching up on a postponed fixture. Internacional will be disappointed not to have taken all three points after leading twice in their match, but an own goal from right-back Fabiano meant the game finished 2-2. Arthur added to the goal he scored in the loss to Palmeiras, helping himself to both goals in a crucial 0-2 victory, which lifted his side from 17th to 14th and a point clear of the relegation zone with eight games to go.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 29</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-29/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-29/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-31T19:02:51-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/10/IMG-20181013-WA0001.jpg" alt="Santos x Corinthians - 13/10/2018" />
                    Round 29’s action kicked off in the Maracana with the Rio derby between Flamengo and Fluminese. Title hopefuls Flamengo brushed aside their city rivals in a comfortable 3-0 win, with Fernando Uribe bagging a double either side of a headed effort from defender Leonardo Duarte&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/10/IMG-20181013-WA0001.jpg" alt="Santos x Corinthians - 13/10/2018" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Round 29’s action kicked off in the Maracana with the Rio derby between Flamengo and Fluminese. Title hopefuls Flamengo brushed aside their city rivals in a comfortable 3-0 win, with Fernando Uribe bagging a double either side of a headed effort from defender Leonardo Duarte da Silva.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another derby, 275 miles down the coast in Santos, saw the home team condemn Corinthians to yet another defeat, their 12th of the season, beating their big-city opponents 1-0 courtesy of Gabriel Barbosa Almeida’s 14th goal of the campaign. Corinthians have now lost their last four games in all competitions, scoring just once in their past five, heaping further pressure on manager Jair Ventura who only joined the side in September. Saturday’s final fixture saw Bahia beat Parana 2-0, with a late brace from Vinicius pulling the team from the north-east clear of the relegation zone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sunday afternoon was dominated by two fixtures involving teams in the top 6, with both matches kicking off at 4pm: Internacional hosted Sao Paulo, while Palmeiras welcomed Gremio to Allianz Parque. Sao Paulo raced into an early lead, Liziero finishing off a fine move with a clever finish, but that was as good as it got for the visitors as Internacional took control of the game and ended up comfortably winning the tie 3-1. Two goals from Leandro Damiao came before a 95th penalty from Nicolas Lopez, awarded after a clumsy challenge from Anderson Martins, which also resulted in a second yellow card for the centre-back. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras stretched their unbeaten run to fourteen games with little drama, beating 5th placed Gremio 2-0 with Deyverson grabbing both goals. Palmeiras have conceded just three goals in the league since losing 1-0 away at Fluminese at the end of July, and it is increasingly difficult to see any way that they can be stopped from winning back the title they last held in 2016. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Sunday’s other matches, Vitoria won 0-1 away at Chapecoense to halt a four-game losing streak and drag themselves out of the relegation places. Vasco da Gama took all three points against Cruzeiro, strikes from Yago Pikachu and Maximiliano Lopez proving the difference. Atletico-PR trounced Sport Recife 4-0 with all of the goals coming in the second half. The Minas Gerais derby did not match its Rio and Sao Paulo based counterparts for entertainment, as Atletico-MG and America-MG played out a scoreless 90 minutes. Botafogo’s Monday night visit to Ceara also ended 0-0 after Arthur missed a penalty for the hosts in the 31st minute.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 28</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-28/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-28/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-26T15:23:17-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/9/IMG-20181007-WA0002.jpg" alt="Morumbi" />
                    Palmeiras tightened their grip on the top spot as they scored two goals in quick succession to beat Sao Paulo 0-2 at the Morumbi on Saturday evening. Despite being only their fourth defeat of the campaign, and their first at home in the league since&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/9/IMG-20181007-WA0002.jpg" alt="Morumbi" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras tightened their grip on the top spot as they scored two goals in quick succession to beat Sao Paulo 0-2 at the Morumbi on Saturday evening. Despite being only their fourth defeat of the campaign, and their first at home in the league since August 2017, Sao Paulo are now four points behind the leaders and paying the price for recent disappointing draws against middling opponents. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Verdao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">went into the derby knowing that victory would put daylight between themselves and the chasing pack following Internacional’s surprise 2-1 loss away at Sport Recife on Friday night. A late goal from Mateus completed an improbable comeback for the league’s second-bottom side after Nicolas Lopez had given the away team the lead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also on Friday night, Flamengo put themselves firmly back into the race for the title as they crushed Corinthians 0-3 at the <em>Itaquerao</em>, inflicting the heaviest home defeat </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Timao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have suffered since moving into the stadium in 2014.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rounding off Friday’s action, Santos beat Vitoria 0-1 courtesy of Carlos Sanchez’s ealy goal, which made it two in two for the Uruguayan midfielder. Vitoria’s Maurice was shown a straight red card late on for using his arm in a challenge with Diego Pituca.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atletico-PR scored within a minute of their match against America-MG, and it proved to be a long afternoon for the team from Minas Gerais as Atletico-PR went on to score three more times in a comfortable 4-0 home victory. After last week’s rip-roaring 5-2 victory over Sport Recife, Atletico-MG came crashing back down to Earth with a disappointing 1-0 loss away at strugglers Chapecoense. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honours were shared in Porto Alegre on Sunday night, as Gremio and Bahia played out an entertaining 2-2 draw, which saw Bahia’s Jackson receive his marching orders following a second yellow card ten minutes after the break. Elber had given Bahia a third minute lead, the striker’s first goal since May, and he then extended the advantage with a second goal in the 67th minute, but ten-man Bahia were unable to hold on and Gremio secured a point with Jael’s 88th minute penalty after Juninho Capixaba had given them hope with a 85th minute strike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday night’s game saw Fluminese hosting, and soundly beating, the league's bottom club Parana. A brace from Jadson sandwiched a goal from Richard Coelho, with a fourth added five minutes before the end by Luciano.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Rio derby between Botafogo and Vasco da Gama took place on Tuesday evening, owing to Botafogo's midweek involvement in the Copa do Brasil, and ended 1-1, with Maximiliano Lopez cancelling out Luis Fernando Moraes dos Santos' opener for Botafogo. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 27</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-27/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-27/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-11T14:17:22-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/8/a68f5cef-a55d-4d2d-9278-06f1b0ccd59e.JPG" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                    A brilliant injury-time double save by Botafogo goalkeeper Saulo denied Sao Paulo all three points and the opportunity to regain top spot as O Tricolor had to twice come from behind to salvage a point in an engrossing 2-2 draw in Rio’s Olympic Stadium on Sunday.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/8/a68f5cef-a55d-4d2d-9278-06f1b0ccd59e.JPG" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A brilliant injury-time double save by Botafogo goalkeeper Saulo denied Sao Paulo all three points and the opportunity to regain top spot as <em>O</em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Tricolor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> had to twice come from behind to salvage a point in an engrossing 2-2 draw in Rio’s Olympic Stadium on Sunday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier in the day, a commanding performance from Palmeiras swept aside Cruzeiro with goals from Lima, Hyoran and Gomez contributing to a 3-1 win, a result which saw Luiz Felipe Scolari’s men climb to the top of the table and ultimately end the weekend in first place following Sao Paulo’s third successive draw.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More bad news for fans of Diego Aguirre’s team was to follow at full-time as Andres D’Alessandro’s 86th minute penalty earned maximum points for fellow title hopefuls Internacional after they came from behind to beat Vitoria 2-1 in Porto Alegre. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elsewhere, supporters who attended Atletico-MG and Sport Recife’s encounter were treated to seven goals as Atletico ran out 5-2 winners courtesy of five different scorers. Corinthians underwhelming season continued with a 0-0 draw away at America-MG on Saturday evening, while Flamengo, whose title aspirations have faded in the past few weeks, and Bahia also shut each other out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gremio claimed the points away at Fluminese, Everton scoring deep into injury time to secure a 0-1 win. Santos left it even later to beat Atletico-PR with Carlos Sanchez scoring the decisive penalty in the 97th minute of a 1-0 victory. At the bottom end of the table, Ceara’s improved form continued with an ultimately comfortable 3-1 win over Chapecoense, which lifted them out of the relegation zone and into 15th place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Parana were unable to capitalise on a fast start against Vasco da Gama in the last match of the round on Monday night, and had to settle for a point after Maximilliano Lopez’s penalty just before half-time cancelled out Alex Santana’s 9th minute opener.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
