<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Futebol Brazil</title>
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com" />
    <updated>2018-10-08T09:55:37-03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ryan O&#x27;Mullan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://futebolbrazil.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>The Times They Are A Changin’</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/The-Times-They-Are-A-Changin/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/The-Times-They-Are-A-Changin/</id>
            <category term="Palmeiras"/>
            <category term="Copa Libertadores"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T09:55:31-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/6/IMG_3187.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Colo-Colo - Copa Libertadores" />
                    Watching your team live is unbeatable. From waking up until kick off your day revolves around that anticipation of the match- often surpassing the quality of football on show. However, watching football in brazil offers some vastly contrasting options when it comes to the period&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/6/IMG_3187.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Colo-Colo - Copa Libertadores" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Watching your team live is unbeatable. From waking up until kick off your day revolves around that anticipation of the match- often surpassing the quality of football on show. However, watching football in brazil offers some vastly contrasting options when it comes to the period of time between that waking up and the first ball being played- and it’s not lazy weekend mornings after one too many caipirinhas that I’m talking about here. This past week I attended two Palmeiras games one at 11am on Sunday and one at 9.45pm on Wednesday. With scheduling that makes the complaints of Friday night football and lunchtime kickoffs in the UK look churlish I decided to investigate what was at the route of the unorthodox timing of games.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A passionate football country Brazil also has a guilty secret- telenovellas! For the unacquainted think Eastenders with a touch of panache and a heap more attractiveness. A focal point of Brazilian daily life these tend to start around 7 and finish around 10pm. So, the land of sexy football has decided that to accommodate their other great televisual passion football should make the move- an idea that a redent arrival to Sao Paulo from London greeted with enthusiasm “ finally a country that appreciates soaps more than football!”.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, as I write this with heavy eyes, my visit to Allianz Parque to watch Palmeiras secure their place in the semis of the Copa Libertadores, meant getting home at 12:30 am and that was without hitting a boteco to celebrate (although we did get to watch the penalties between Bahia and Botafogo in our taxi as it hurtled to our neighborhood – note to anyone trying this….make sure your driver doesn’t support one of the teams playingas it makes for a rollercoaster of a journey home!!</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 11 am kickoff is a bit better on the sleep patterns and brings a more family oriented crowd- although I think the guys behind us on the terraces took it as a chance to catch a game on the way home from a night out! The upside of this seem to be that in a country where Sunday lunch at mum’s is still a must you can catch a game the downside, for players and pasty faced scots, is that the game takes place in the searing midday heat. At the Pacaembu this proved a particular problem seeing as there is no escape on the terraces.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, the long and the short of it is that watching football in Brazil is great fun – day or night- but don’t expect much sleep!</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Estadio Rodolfo Crespi: A Brief History</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Hardwicke</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/industrialisation-protest-and-football/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/industrialisation-protest-and-football/</id>
            <category term="Brazil"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T09:45:31-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/1/Estadio-Rodolfo-Crespi.jpg" alt="" />
                    Industrialisation, Protest and Football For those of us raised on the sanitised, corporate world of top-flight European football, visiting the Estadio Rodolfo Crespi feels like stepping back in time: the stark white concrete that forms the stands; the wire fence separating fans from the pitch;&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/1/Estadio-Rodolfo-Crespi.jpg" alt="" />
                <p class="align-center"><strong>Industrialisation, Protest and Football</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For those of us raised on the sanitised, corporate world of top-flight European football, visiting the Estadio Rodolfo Crespi feels like stepping back in time: the stark white concrete that forms the stands; the wire fence separating fans from the pitch; the repeated crowd surges towards (and indeed, up) the fence at exciting moments; the sheer lack of modernity. A trip to the working-class neighbourhood of Mooca, East of Sao Paulo’s historic centre and home to Clube Atletico Juventus, gives the thrilling sense of entering an era of football long-forgotten in other parts of the world. Nowadays, Juve ply their trade in the third tier of Sao Paulo’s state system, the Paulista Serie A3, but this humble position masks the club’s rich history and influential role in the development of this corner of Sao Paulo.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The development of the ground - a tale of immigration, industrialisation and revolt - only adds to the romantic atmosphere within. Moreover, it is a history that can be seen, visibly, not only in the past triumphs inscribed on the walls, or the plaque commemorating the scoring of Pele's greatest ever goal, but in the looming presence of the Rodolfo Crespi Cotonificio - the imposing former textiles factory that stands tall over one end of the ground despite being a substantial two blocks away.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rodolfo Crespi was an Italian immigrant with powerful connections. Given the title 'Count' by the King of Italy, he is alleged to have counted Mussolini among his influential friends. Bringing looms to Brazil, he established the Cotonoficio in 1897: with an area of 50,000 square meters, it became one of the largest factories in Sao Paulo’s industrialisation. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crespi's workers, many of whom were Italian, enjoyed playing football on the area of grass where the stadium now sits. In 1917, Crespi’s employees were among those to take part in Brazil’s first national strike. Indeed, there are locals who will tell you the strike’s origins can be traced to the Cotonoficio. The Italian Count’s response was to essentially hand over this piece of land to his workers, and in 1924 the club, initially taking the name of the factory, was formally established. In 1929 they reached the Campeonato Paulista, the top division of Sao Paulo football and the oldest established league in Brazil, and became Clube Atletico Juventus.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ground was initially built in the years between 1925 and 1929, with later alterations to the 4,000 capacity venue completed in 1941. It has been the home of Juve throughout their 93 years and witness to their modest success, which includes two state second division titles, a state cup and a national second division title. In addition, the Estadio has played host to a number of ‘giant killings’ for which the team has gained the nickname Moleque Travesso (the little trickster).</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For neutral observers, it is arguably more famous for the events of August 2</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nd</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 1959, when an eighteen-year-old Pele, playing for Santos, scored what he considers the most beautiful goal of his career (since there is no footage of the goal, Pele had a </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xD70ECy5E2k"><span style="font-weight: 400;">digital simulation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made. For Juve fans, the ground is simply “Javari” after the street which houses both the stadium and the factory. Here at Futebol.Brazil, it still feels like another world.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Wet Wednesday in Sao Paulo</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/a-wet-wednesday-in-sao-paulo/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/a-wet-wednesday-in-sao-paulo/</id>
            <category term="Palmeiras"/>
            <category term="Copa Brazil"/>
            <category term="Bahia"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T09:51:22-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/5/oIMG_6246.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Bahia - Copa Brazil" />
                    “But could he hack it on a wet Wednesday in Stoke?”. The oft asked sometimes badly answered question of Messi et al when lazy journalists and ex-pros debate the merits of South Americans being able to handle the rigors of facing Ryan Shawcross and his&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/5/oIMG_6246.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Bahia - Copa Brazil" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But could he hack it on a wet Wednesday in Stoke?”. The oft asked sometimes badly answered question of Messi et al when lazy journalists and ex-pros debate the merits of  South Americans being able to handle the rigors of facing Ryan Shawcross and his band of merry hatchet men in the apparently torrential middle of England. The answer, in case anyone is wondering, is yes. I can answer this with authority because </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A. Messi is quite good at football and Stoke aren’t and <br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">B. Football in Brazil isn’t all sunshine and rainbows on the beach. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This brings me to my first experience of the Copa Brasil. This was indeed a wet Wednesday, not in the Potteries but in Sao Paulo. Played at Pacaembu, Sao Paulo’s city owned stadium-for-hire-when-some-popstar-has-booked-yours, we set off for a night of football viewed from the terracing and in 10c drizzle.  Terracing, still somewhat a novelty for a British fan whose football watching was for the most part post-hilborough, holds a certain magic quality. It harks back to days when football was played by men who enjoyed pints after a game (sometimes before and during) . Days that probably never really existed but that in imagination hold the key to “real football”, before the gentrification with such onerous afflictions as safety and women’s’ toilets. An uncovered antiquity holding 40k the Pacembu hosted the word cup -first time round- and has, needless to say seen more glamorous fixtures than this quarter final between Palmeiras and Bahia. A must win for a newly returned Scholari the game started with optimism from the Palmeiras fans. As the rain kicked in and the Porcos were unable to assert any form of dominance this hope soon turned to frustration and several “nossa senoras” from the less than impressed crowd. With time ticking on and the very near and terrifying prospect of extra time, penalties and a cold approaching, finally the deadlock was broken by Dudu. A chilly Sao Paulo winter’s evening was finally warmed by the only decent piece of play and the idea of being in my toasty bed was now becoming real. The final twenty minutes was played out on a slick yet slow surface and with my prayers of no further goals silently murmured the seconds dripped away like the rain through my inappropriately optimistic Celtic hoodie. These prayers were answered and as we traipsed out of the Pacembu I was left contemplating if Peter Crouch could have hacked this turgid affair on a wet Wednesday in Sao Paulo. Would Stephen Ireland* have invented another granny and her untimely demise to get out of the rain? Would Darren Fletcher be dreaming of the tropical climes of Edinburgh? Would Berahino** be able to keep up his goal per 300 game ratio? I guess we will never know.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*At time of writing Stephen Ireland is currently no longer at Stoke, having been released after relegation. The status of his granmother’s maginary or not is unknown.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">** After writing but before we got our arses in gear to get a website started up Beranhino (sounds quite Brazilian no?) has scored a goal. He is still shite.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
