<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Futebol Brazil</title>
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com" />
    <updated>2018-10-22T19:03:43-03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ryan O&#x27;Mullan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://futebolbrazil.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 30</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-30/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-30/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-22T19:03:33-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/11/IMG-20181022-WA0011.jpg" alt="Palmeiras x Ceara - 21/10/18" />
                    Palmeiras managed to hold on to their lead and secure all three points in Sunday’s 2-1 victory over Ceara, despite having forward Deyverson dismissed in first-half injury time for an inexplicable chest-height studs-up challenge on Richardson. A double from Bruno Henrique was enough for the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/11/IMG-20181022-WA0011.jpg" alt="Palmeiras x Ceara - 21/10/18" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras managed to hold on to their lead and secure all three points in Sunday’s 2-1 victory over Ceara, despite having forward Deyverson dismissed in first-half injury time for an inexplicable chest-height studs-up challenge on Richardson. A double from Bruno Henrique was enough for the home team, Arthur replying for Ceara in the 55th minute.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Title rivals Flamengo kept the pressure on with an impressive result away at bottom side Parana. Three second-half strikes followed Lucas Paqueta’s 19th minute openers to give </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Mengao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a comfortable trip back to Rio de Janeiro, and keep the gap at the top down to four points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s matches saw America-MG play out yet another draw, their fifth in seven games, with Gremio. The match finished 1-1 after Jean Pyerre’s penalty drew Gremio level after Juninho scored for the hosts. Bahia took maximum points from their trip to Botafogo, courtesy of Edigar Junio’s strike just minutes after coming on as a second-half sub. Sao Paulo and Atletico-PR were unable to find a way past each other in an unremarkable game at the Morumbi stadium, which must surely spell the end of any lingering title aspirations for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Tricolor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sport Recife earned a vital win in their attempt to avoid relegation, beating Vasco da Game 2-1 and with enough to spare to afford a 94th minute missed penalty by Gabriel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Sunday afternoon, Vitoria hosted an out-of-form Corinthians side and played out an entertaining 2-2 draw, with a goal apiece scored in frantic injury time period. Roger thought that he had secured the win for the Sao Paulo based side with his 91st minute goal, until Neilton snatched a point for Vitoria in the 93rd minute. Fluminese beat Atletico-MG 1-0 with Luciano scoring in the 63rd minute after Fabio Santos had missed a penalty for the Atletico-MG at the start of the second half. Cruzeiro had no problem dispatching Chapecoense on Sunday evening, with three first half goals making for an easy three points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round’s last fixture saw Internacional host Santos hoping to keep within touching distance of the top two. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 29</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-29/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-29/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-18T22:43:43-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/10/IMG-20181013-WA0001.jpg" alt="Santos x Corinthians - 13/10/2018" />
                    Round 29’s action kicked off in the Maracana with the Rio derby between Flamengo and Fluminese. Title hopefuls Flamengo brushed aside their city rivals in a comfortable 3-0 win, with Fernando Uribe bagging a double either side of a headed effort from defender Leonardo Duarte&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/10/IMG-20181013-WA0001.jpg" alt="Santos x Corinthians - 13/10/2018" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Round 29’s action kicked off in the Maracana with the Rio derby between Flamengo and Fluminese. Title hopefuls Flamengo brushed aside their city rivals in a comfortable 3-0 win, with Fernando Uribe bagging a double either side of a headed effort from defender Leonardo Duarte da Silva.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another derby, 275 miles down the coast in Santos, saw the home team condemn Corinthians to yet another defeat, their 12th of the season, beating their big-city opponents 1-0 courtesy of Gabriel Barbosa Almeida’s 14th goal of the campaign. Corinthians have now lost their last four games in all competitions, scoring just once in their past five, heaping further pressure on manager Jair Ventura who only joined the side in September. Saturday’s final fixture saw Bahia beat Parana 2-0, with a late brace from Vinicius pulling the team from the north-east clear of the relegation zone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sunday afternoon was dominated by two fixtures involving teams in the top 6, with both matches kicking off at 4pm: Internacional hosted Sao Paulo, while Palmeiras welcomed Gremio to Allianz Parque. Sao Paulo raced into an early lead, Liziero finishing off a fine move with a clever finish, but that was as good as it got for the visitors as Internacional took control of the game and ended up comfortably winning the tie 3-1. Two goals from Leandro Damiao came before a 95th penalty from Nicolas Lopez, awarded after a clumsy challenge from Anderson Martins, which also resulted in a second yellow card for the centre-back. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras stretched their unbeaten run to fourteen games with little drama, beating 5th placed Gremio 2-0 with Deyverson grabbing both goals. Palmeiras have conceded just three goals in the league since losing 1-0 away at Fluminese at the end of July, and it is increasingly difficult to see any way that they can be stopped from winning back the title they last held in 2016. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Sunday’s other matches, Vitoria won 0-1 away at Chapecoense to halt a four-game losing streak and drag themselves out of the relegation places. Vasco da Gama took all three points against Cruzeiro, strikes from Yago Pikachu and Maximiliano Lopez proving the difference. Atletico-PR trounced Sport Recife 4-0 with all of the goals coming in the second half. The Minas Gerais derby did not match its Rio and Sao Paulo based counterparts for entertainment, as Atletico-MG and America-MG played out a scoreless 90 minutes. Botafogo’s Monday night visit to Ceara also ended 0-0 after Arthur missed a penalty for the hosts in the 31st minute.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 28</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-28/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-28/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-11T14:16:09-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/9/IMG-20181007-WA0002.jpg" alt="Morumbi" />
                    Palmeiras tightened their grip on the top spot as they scored two goals in quick succession to beat Sao Paulo 0-2 at the Morumbi on Saturday evening. Despite being only their fourth defeat of the campaign, and their first at home in the league since&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/9/IMG-20181007-WA0002.jpg" alt="Morumbi" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras tightened their grip on the top spot as they scored two goals in quick succession to beat Sao Paulo 0-2 at the Morumbi on Saturday evening. Despite being only their fourth defeat of the campaign, and their first at home in the league since August 2017, Sao Paulo are now four points behind the leaders and paying the price for recent disappointing draws against middling opponents. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Verdao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">went into the derby knowing that victory would put daylight between themselves and the chasing pack following Internacional’s surprise 2-1 loss away at Sport Recife on Friday night. A late goal from Mateus completed an improbable comeback for the league’s second-bottom side after Nicolas Lopez had given the away team the lead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also on Friday night, Flamengo put themselves firmly back into the race for the title as they crushed Corinthians 0-3 at the <em>Itaquerao</em>, inflicting the heaviest home defeat </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Timao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have suffered since moving into the stadium in 2014.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rounding off Friday’s action, Santos beat Vitoria 0-1 courtesy of Carlos Sanchez’s ealy goal, which made it two in two for the Uruguayan midfielder. Vitoria’s Maurice was shown a straight red card late on for using his arm in a challenge with Diego Pituca.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atletico-PR scored within a minute of their match against America-MG, and it proved to be a long afternoon for the team from Minas Gerais as Atletico-PR went on to score three more times in a comfortable 4-0 home victory. After last week’s rip-roaring 5-2 victory over Sport Recife, Atletico-MG came crashing back down to Earth with a disappointing 1-0 loss away at strugglers Chapecoense. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honours were shared in Porto Alegre on Sunday night, as Gremio and Bahia played out an entertaining 2-2 draw, which saw Bahia’s Jackson receive his marching orders following a second yellow card ten minutes after the break. Elber had given Bahia a third minute lead, the striker’s first goal since May, and he then extended the advantage with a second goal in the 67th minute, but ten-man Bahia were unable to hold on and Gremio secured a point with Jael’s 88th minute penalty after Juninho Capixaba had given them hope with a 85th minute strike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday night’s game saw Fluminese hosting, and soundly beating, the league's bottom club Parana. A brace from Jadson sandwiched a goal from Richard Coelho, with a fourth added five minutes before the end by Luciano.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Rio derby between Botafogo and Vasco da Gama took place on Tuesday evening, owing to Botafogo's midweek involvement in the Copa do Brasil, and ended 1-1, with Maximiliano Lopez cancelling out Luis Fernando Moraes dos Santos' opener for Botafogo. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 27</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-27/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-27/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-10-11T14:17:22-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/8/a68f5cef-a55d-4d2d-9278-06f1b0ccd59e.JPG" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                    A brilliant injury-time double save by Botafogo goalkeeper Saulo denied Sao Paulo all three points and the opportunity to regain top spot as O Tricolor had to twice come from behind to salvage a point in an engrossing 2-2 draw in Rio’s Olympic Stadium on Sunday.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/8/a68f5cef-a55d-4d2d-9278-06f1b0ccd59e.JPG" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A brilliant injury-time double save by Botafogo goalkeeper Saulo denied Sao Paulo all three points and the opportunity to regain top spot as <em>O</em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Tricolor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> had to twice come from behind to salvage a point in an engrossing 2-2 draw in Rio’s Olympic Stadium on Sunday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier in the day, a commanding performance from Palmeiras swept aside Cruzeiro with goals from Lima, Hyoran and Gomez contributing to a 3-1 win, a result which saw Luiz Felipe Scolari’s men climb to the top of the table and ultimately end the weekend in first place following Sao Paulo’s third successive draw.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More bad news for fans of Diego Aguirre’s team was to follow at full-time as Andres D’Alessandro’s 86th minute penalty earned maximum points for fellow title hopefuls Internacional after they came from behind to beat Vitoria 2-1 in Porto Alegre. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elsewhere, supporters who attended Atletico-MG and Sport Recife’s encounter were treated to seven goals as Atletico ran out 5-2 winners courtesy of five different scorers. Corinthians underwhelming season continued with a 0-0 draw away at America-MG on Saturday evening, while Flamengo, whose title aspirations have faded in the past few weeks, and Bahia also shut each other out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gremio claimed the points away at Fluminese, Everton scoring deep into injury time to secure a 0-1 win. Santos left it even later to beat Atletico-PR with Carlos Sanchez scoring the decisive penalty in the 97th minute of a 1-0 victory. At the bottom end of the table, Ceara’s improved form continued with an ultimately comfortable 3-1 win over Chapecoense, which lifted them out of the relegation zone and into 15th place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Parana were unable to capitalise on a fast start against Vasco da Gama in the last match of the round on Monday night, and had to settle for a point after Maximilliano Lopez’s penalty just before half-time cancelled out Alex Santana’s 9th minute opener.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Party at the Pacaembu?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/party-at-the-pacaembu/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/party-at-the-pacaembu/</id>
            <category term="Pacaembu"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T21:20:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/7/pacaembu.jpg" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                    Most football fans will have a first memory of when they fell in love with the samba football of the Brazil national team. Maybe it was the 70s teams with Pele and the boys. Perhaps it was Romario skipping it into the net in 1994,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/7/pacaembu.jpg" alt="Pacaembu Stadium" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most football fans will have a first memory of when they fell in love with the samba football of the Brazil national team. Maybe it was the 70s teams with Pele and the boys. Perhaps it was Romario skipping it into the net in 1994, or four years later when Ronaldo and his gang knocked a ball around an airport. For me it was around 1996 when I was gifted a history of Brazilian football on VHS. That tape was worn down to the nub by the end of the year, and a love of the greats of Brazilian football was born. Somewhere on that video was grainy footage of the 1950 World Cup held in Brazil: the 199,854 people packed into the Maracana, the skills of Balthazar, Zizinho and Ademir, the heartbreak of a nation losing out to Uruguay. One of the host stadiums that year was a then 10-year-old Pacaembu. Fast-forward almost 70 years and the old stadium is still going strong. It was here that we set off to watch Santos v Gremio last Thursday. One of the great homes of Brazilian football hosting the team of Pele - what more could one want?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was Santos’ first return to the stadium since being eliminated from the Copa Libertadores in controversial circumstances. The ensuing riot meant that police presence was high, but a friendly enough atmosphere was present inside and outside the ground. The 7pm kickoff meant that the ground slowly filled up as the first-half progressed and, to be honest, those arriving late missed very little. The same could be said if someone had rocked up after the final whistle. Bar a potential home penalty towards the end, this was a turgid late-season affair. Gremio, with title aspirations now dented, looked the more technically proficient without ever looking dangerous. The current continental champions did nothing to suggest that their exit from the competition last month was undeserved, and it leaves the race at the top with three main contenders. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Times They Are A Changin’</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/the-times-they-are-a-changin/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/the-times-they-are-a-changin/</id>
            <category term="Palmeiras"/>
            <category term="Copa Libertadores"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T21:19:52-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/6/IMG_3187.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Colo-Colo - Copa Libertadores" />
                    Watching your team live is unbeatable. From waking up until kick off, your day revolves around that anticipation of the match - often surpassing the quality of football on show. However, watching football in Brazil offers some vastly contrasting options when it comes to the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/6/IMG_3187.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Colo-Colo - Copa Libertadores" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Watching your team live is unbeatable. From waking up until kick off, your day revolves around that anticipation of the match - often surpassing the quality of football on show. However, watching football in Brazil offers some vastly contrasting options when it comes to the period of time between waking up and the first ball being played - and it’s not lazy weekend mornings after one too many caipirinhas that I’m talking about here. This past week I attended two Palmeiras games; one at 11am on Sunday and one at 9.45pm on Wednesday. With scheduling that makes the complaints about Friday night football and lunchtime kick-offs in the UK look churlish, I decided to investigate what was at the root of the unorthodox timing of games.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A passionate football country, Brazil also has a guilty secret - telenovelas! For the unacquainted, think Eastenders with a touch of panache and a heap more attractiveness. A focal point of Brazilian daily life, these tend to start around 7pm and finish around 10pm. So, the land of sexy football has decided that in order to accommodate their other great televisual passion, football should make the move - an idea that a recent arrival to Sao Paulo from London greeted with enthusiasm, “Finally, a country that appreciates soaps more than football!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I write this with heavy eyes, my visit to Allianz Parque to watch Palmeiras secure their place in the semis of the Copa Libertadores meant getting home at 12:30am, and that was without hitting a boteco to celebrate (although we did get to watch the penalties between Bahia and Botafogo in our taxi as it hurtled towards our neighborhood – note to anyone trying this….make sure your driver doesn’t support one of the teams playing as it makes for a rollercoaster of a journey home!!)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 11am kickoff is a bit better on the sleep patterns, and brings out a more family-oriented crowd - although I think the guys behind us on the terrace took it as a chance to catch a game on the way home from a night out! The upside of this seems to be that in a country where Sunday lunch at mum’s is still a must, you can catch a game. The downside, for players and pasty faced Scots, is that the game takes place in the searing midday heat. At the Pacaembu this proved a particular problem, seeing as there is no escape on the terraces.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, the long and the short of it is that watching football in Brazil is great fun – day or night - but don’t expect much sleep!</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Estadio Rodolfo Crespi: A Brief History</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Hardwicke</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/industrialisation-protest-and-football/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/industrialisation-protest-and-football/</id>
            <category term="Brazil"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T09:45:31-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/1/Estadio-Rodolfo-Crespi.jpg" alt="" />
                    Industrialisation, Protest and Football For those of us raised on the sanitised, corporate world of top-flight European football, visiting the Estadio Rodolfo Crespi feels like stepping back in time: the stark white concrete that forms the stands; the wire fence separating fans from the pitch;&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/1/Estadio-Rodolfo-Crespi.jpg" alt="" />
                <p class="align-center"><strong>Industrialisation, Protest and Football</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For those of us raised on the sanitised, corporate world of top-flight European football, visiting the Estadio Rodolfo Crespi feels like stepping back in time: the stark white concrete that forms the stands; the wire fence separating fans from the pitch; the repeated crowd surges towards (and indeed, up) the fence at exciting moments; the sheer lack of modernity. A trip to the working-class neighbourhood of Mooca, East of Sao Paulo’s historic centre and home to Clube Atletico Juventus, gives the thrilling sense of entering an era of football long-forgotten in other parts of the world. Nowadays, Juve ply their trade in the third tier of Sao Paulo’s state system, the Paulista Serie A3, but this humble position masks the club’s rich history and influential role in the development of this corner of Sao Paulo.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The development of the ground - a tale of immigration, industrialisation and revolt - only adds to the romantic atmosphere within. Moreover, it is a history that can be seen, visibly, not only in the past triumphs inscribed on the walls, or the plaque commemorating the scoring of Pele's greatest ever goal, but in the looming presence of the Rodolfo Crespi Cotonificio - the imposing former textiles factory that stands tall over one end of the ground despite being a substantial two blocks away.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rodolfo Crespi was an Italian immigrant with powerful connections. Given the title 'Count' by the King of Italy, he is alleged to have counted Mussolini among his influential friends. Bringing looms to Brazil, he established the Cotonoficio in 1897: with an area of 50,000 square meters, it became one of the largest factories in Sao Paulo’s industrialisation. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crespi's workers, many of whom were Italian, enjoyed playing football on the area of grass where the stadium now sits. In 1917, Crespi’s employees were among those to take part in Brazil’s first national strike. Indeed, there are locals who will tell you the strike’s origins can be traced to the Cotonoficio. The Italian Count’s response was to essentially hand over this piece of land to his workers, and in 1924 the club, initially taking the name of the factory, was formally established. In 1929 they reached the Campeonato Paulista, the top division of Sao Paulo football and the oldest established league in Brazil, and became Clube Atletico Juventus.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ground was initially built in the years between 1925 and 1929, with later alterations to the 4,000 capacity venue completed in 1941. It has been the home of Juve throughout their 93 years and witness to their modest success, which includes two state second division titles, a state cup and a national second division title. In addition, the Estadio has played host to a number of ‘giant killings’ for which the team has gained the nickname Moleque Travesso (the little trickster).</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For neutral observers, it is arguably more famous for the events of August 2</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nd</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 1959, when an eighteen-year-old Pele, playing for Santos, scored what he considers the most beautiful goal of his career (since there is no footage of the goal, Pele had a </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xD70ECy5E2k"><span style="font-weight: 400;">digital simulation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made. For Juve fans, the ground is simply “Javari” after the street which houses both the stadium and the factory. Here at Futebol.Brazil, it still feels like another world.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Wet Wednesday in Sao Paulo</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/a-wet-wednesday-in-sao-paulo/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/a-wet-wednesday-in-sao-paulo/</id>
            <category term="Palmeiras"/>
            <category term="Copa Brazil"/>
            <category term="Bahia"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T21:19:45-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/5/oIMG_6246.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Bahia - Copa Brazil" />
                    “But could he hack it on a wet Wednesday in Stoke?”. The oft asked, sometimes badly answered question of Messi et al, when lazy journalists and ex-pros debate the merits of South Americans being able to handle the rigours of facing Ryan Shawcross and his&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/5/oIMG_6246.JPG" alt="Palmeiras vs Bahia - Copa Brazil" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But could he hack it on a wet Wednesday in Stoke?”. The oft asked, sometimes badly answered question of Messi et al, when lazy journalists and ex-pros debate the merits of South Americans being able to handle the rigours of facing Ryan Shawcross and his band of merry hatchet-men in the apparently torrential middle of England. The answer, in case anyone is wondering, is yes. I can answer this with authority because:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A. Messi is quite good at football and Stoke aren’t, and <br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">B. Football in Brazil isn’t all sunshine and rainbows on the beach. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This brings me to my first experience of the Copa Brasil. This was indeed a wet Wednesday, not in the Potteries but in Sao Paulo. Played at Pacaembu, Sao Paulo’s city owned stadium-for-hire-when-some-popstar-has-booked-yours, we set off for a night of football viewed from the terracing and in 10 degree drizzle. Terracing, still somewhat a novelty for a British fan whose football watching was for the most part post-Hillsborough, holds a certain magic quality. It harks back to days when football was played by men who enjoyed pints after a game (sometimes before and during). Days that probably never really existed, but that in imagination hold the key to “real football”, before the gentrification with such onerous afflictions as 'safety' and 'women’s toilets'. An uncovered antiquity holding 40k, the Pacembu hosted the Word Cup - first time round - and has, needless to say, seen more glamorous fixtures than this quarter-final between Palmeiras and Bahia. A must win for a newly returned Scolari, the game started with optimism from the Palmeiras fans. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the rain kicked in and <em>Os</em> <em>Porcos</em> were unable to assert any form of dominance, this hope soon turned to frustration and several "Nossa Senhoras!" from the less than impressed crowd. With time ticking on, and the very near and terrifying prospect of extra time, penalties and a cold approaching, finally the deadlock was broken by Dudu. A chilly Sao Paulo winter’s evening was finally warmed by the only decent piece of play, and the idea of being in my toasty bed was now becoming real. The final twenty minutes was played out on a slick yet slow surface, and with my prayers for no further goals silently murmured, the seconds dripped away like the rain through my inappropriately optimistic Celtic hoodie. These prayers were answered, and as we traipsed out of the Pacembu I was left contemplating if Peter Crouch could have hacked this turgid affair on a wet Wednesday in Sao Paulo. Would Stephen Ireland* have invented another granny and her untimely demise to get out of the rain? Would Darren Fletcher be dreaming of the tropical climes of Edinburgh? Would Saido Berahino** be able to keep up his goal per 300 game ratio? I guess we will never know.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*At time of writing Stephen Ireland is currently no longer at Stoke, having been released after relegation. The status of his grandmothers, imaginary or not, is unknown.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">** After writing, but before we got our arses in gear to get a website started up, Saido Beranhino (sounds quite Brazilian, no?) scored a goal. He is still shite.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
