<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Futebol Brazil</title>
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com" />
    <updated>2019-02-17T09:31:36-03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ryan O&#x27;Mullan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://futebolbrazil.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>A Fan&#x27;s View- Santos</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/a-fans-view-santos/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/a-fans-view-santos/</id>
            <category term="Sao Paulo"/>
            <category term="Santos"/>
            <category term="Pele"/>
            <category term="Fans"/>

        <updated>2019-01-30T16:02:52-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/25/cc92666b-bd08-4eb3-b09d-621bdc643e43.JPG" alt="" />
                    Santos Situated an hour to the East of Sao Paulo, the coastal city of Santos isn’t exactly picture postcard stuff. A city forged on a working class port, it is the industrial mouth of the financial metropolis that is the state capital. Santos does have&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/25/cc92666b-bd08-4eb3-b09d-621bdc643e43.JPG" alt="" />
                <p>Santos</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Situated an hour to the East of Sao Paulo, the coastal city of Santos isn’t exactly picture postcard stuff. A city forged on a working class port, it is the industrial mouth of the financial metropolis that is the state capital. Santos does have a certain claim when it comes to beauty though. What it lacks in natural finesse it more than makes up for in the footballing variety. Home of Pele and Neymar, this city can claim the World’s best (in Brazilian eyes at least) and most expensive players respectively. With the latest academy prodigy, Rodrygo, on his way for $50 million to Real Madrid it seems that the boys from the beach are more than a match for their big city Paulista rivals: Corinthians; Palmeiras; and Sao Paulo. I met up with Xande, a life long fan, to find out why he chose to support the ”Peixe”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Having written recently about how I started supporting Palmeiras I was keen to find out if there was any intrigue behind Xande’s decision to support Santos. The story I hear is one that has played out in families around the world since the game began “My father and grandfather supported them. They didn’t force me into it but they were delighted when I started being fascinated with Santos aged 5.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although not an unusual story it <em>is</em> relatively unusual to be brought up within the Sao Paulo city limits and not go for one of the” big three”. Xande explains that you have a bit of a mixed identity when you choose to be a Santastico      “ Some see us as a the laid back beach team but we are also very much a Sao Paulo team. We have a big rivalry with Sao Paulo, Palmeiras and Corinthians”. This is borne out in Santos’ choice of home. In theory they play their home games at the 16,000 seater Estadio Urbano Caldeira in Santos. However, with so many of their fans living and working in Sao Paulo they often opt to play in the much larger Pacaembu just off Paulista Avenue in Central Sao Paulo.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Santos have had some highs and lows over the years and we start chatting about Xande’s life as a fan. He vents his frustration at the media’s perception of them as a little team and their disrespectful attitude. Another disappointment he feels lies not with the club but their treatment in last year’s Copa Libertadores. COMEBOL decided to award Independiente of Argentina a 3-0 win for the first leg due to the fielding of an illegible player. “ There were no Brazilian’s on the committee that made that decision and their own website said the player could play” he laments. The timing of the decision was disastrous too; just before kickoff of a second leg which should have been poised for a thriller. “This happened an hour before kickoff of the second leg. The atmosphere was bad and as the game went on the ultras started setting off “bombs”. As each one of these went off the crowd got more agitated until they started fighting and the game was abandoned “. Did he fear for his safety? “No, not really. The riot was at the other end of the stadium. On the way out the police were firing water cannons at fans but we were far enough away - so much so that people were using the spray to cool down and dance in the street!”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>We turn to happier moments. When asked about his favourite game there isn’t a moment’s hesitation “1995 Brasileirao. It was my first time at the stadium. At that time the championship was decided by a play-off. In the first leg of the semi-final we lost 4-1 away at Fluminense. With the game “lost” there were tickets available for the return leg. Me and a few friends decided to go along and never regretted it. We won 5-2 and ended up going through. Although we lost the final to Botafogo the semi-final game was amazing. “</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The hero of that 5-2 victory was Giovanni, latterly of Barcelona and Olympiakos fame. “ He was the main reason we won that day. We still call him the Messiah at Santos”. A recent young Santos player making his way to Europe is Rodrygo. “ He’s too young to star at the moment but hopefully he can get time to learn. Neymar left as a more complete article having just won the Copa Libertadores. He was in a great team too. Unfortunately back then we had to wait half a year between winning the Libertadores and the Club World Cup. Most of our stars had left for Europe and we ended up getting embarrassed by Barcelona 5-0” . And what of Neymar, does he have a claim to the thrown of the great Pele? “Hahaha, no way! No one comes near. Argentinian’s might say Maradona but no way. Pele was the best of the best team”.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Season Review - Part Two</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/season-review-part-two/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/season-review-part-two/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-12-19T18:49:42-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/24/Screen-Shot-2018-12-17-at-15.12.16.png" alt="Bahia Fans at Itaquerao" />
                    Now we turn to matters at the wrong end of the table. In some ways, the battle to beat the drop was more exciting than the title race, once it became clear that the green machine was going to sweep all before it, leaving little&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/24/Screen-Shot-2018-12-17-at-15.12.16.png" alt="Bahia Fans at Itaquerao" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now we turn to matters at the wrong end of the table. In some ways, the battle to beat the drop was more exciting than the title race, once it became clear that the green machine was going to sweep all before it, leaving little excitement for those not of a palmeirense persuasion. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rebaixamento </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to Serie B means a drop in revenue, waning attendance figures and, worst of all, the loss of face. There are four teams that have never been relegated from the top flight, and they certainly don’t let opposing fans forget it. Cruzeiro, Flamengo, Santos and Sao Paulo are the four that have been ever present since entering Serie A. It’s worth noting, however, that relegation doesn’t seem to have as damaging an effect on teams as it does when sides slip out of the Premier League. As mentioned in Part One, Internacional bounced back at the first time of asking, managing a third-place finish this year, and it was only in 2013 that this year’s champions were languishing in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a segunda divisao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.   </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></i></p>
<br>
<p><strong>11th - Bahia</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike the notoriously thick and humid air of their home state, Bahia blew hot and cold this season but will almost certainly feel that are more positives than negatives to take back to the north-east with them. A poor start to the season was followed by a two month unbeaten spell, which abruptly nose-dived into a run of 2 wins in 10 matches. Though they struggled to stand up to the teams at the top of the table, they showed themselves to be capable of getting important wins from the sides around them and they’ll take heart from the improvement in performances towards the end of the season. </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Gregore</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>12th - Fluminese</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With their stadium-sharing rivals, Flamengo, flying high at the top of the league, it was important that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Fluzao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at least got the Rio derbies right. With six opportunities to restore a measure of local pride (vs. Botafogo and Vasco da Gama, as well as Flamengo), they managed just one win and one draw, which is just about right given the underwhelming performances from a team that really should be doing better. With just 32 goals all season, the third lowest in the league, this was a season to forget for everyone involved with a team that were national champions not so long ago in 2012. </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: D-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Pedro</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>13th - Corinthians</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With two titles in three years, expectations are never less than sky-high around the Itaquerao, and as such a title defence this limp is sure to hurt. Just two away wins all season, allied with four losses at their usually fortress-like home ground, made for a thoroughly miserable 2018 for the self-styled </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Timao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Poor performances on the pitch were not helped by matters off it, as the board conducted their own little managerial merry-go-round. Fabio Carille’s early season departure for Al-Wehda led to the appointment of Omar Loss, who was replaced by Jair Ventura following a run of poor form, who was then sacked at the end of the season for failing to arrest the decline. Fabio Carille has been re-appointed manager for the upcoming season, and fans will be hoping for a return to form under the title-winning boss.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: E</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Cassio</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>14th - Chapecoense</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 was always likely to be a difficult season for the Santa Catarina based side. After the outpouring of support from across the globe, multiple player loans and a cathartic effort to keep the club moving forward in the aftermath of the horrific airline disaster at the tail end of the 2016 season culminated in an astonishing eighth-place finish in 2017, the season after the one before was at risk of some sizeable aftershocks. As expected, it proved a challenge, but one which </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chape</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rose to admirably. Reasonably strong home form saw them able to balance out a very leaky defence and finish two points clear of relegation. A final day home win secured their Serie A status for another season, and there will have been few, even amongst the Sao Paulo fans gathered in the away end, that begrudged them that.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C+</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Wellington Paulista</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>15th - Ceara</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Back amongst the big boys for the first time since 2011, Ceara were widely tipped to make a quick return to the second tier. Without a win after 12 rounds, it looked like the doom-mongers were right, and the ‘Big Grandpa’ (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vozao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) of the northeast would roll over and accept their fate as local rivals Sport Recife rolled up to collect their 3 points. The match proved to be a turning point and sparked Ceara’s season into life. This vital win saw their home in Fortaleza become a ground that no one wanted to visit, with six wins and five draws in their remaining twelve home games enough to keep them up with a couple of points to spare.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Everson</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>16th - Vasco da Gama</strong></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Gigante da Colina</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, one of the most storied and popular teams in all Brazil, have become that most confusing of things, for fans at least, the yo-yo club. Relegated in 2013, they came straight back up again, only to be promptly relegated on their return. Once again they lifted themselves from the canvas, Tyson Fury style, to regain a place at the top table at the first time of asking. An emotional rollercoaster for supporters, which some will see as more enjoyable than season after season of mid-table obscurity. Last season saw them buck the trend and enjoy an excellent campaign, finishing 7th with continental competition their reward. Perhaps it was too much to expect for Vasco to build on that platform, but by all measures this was another poor season and they were fortunate that the final round of fixtures fell in their favour. Nobody was surprised when they earned a goalless draw away at fellow strugglers Ceara - a result which confirmed the survival of both sides.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: D</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Maxi Lopez</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>17th - Sport Recife</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So to the clubs that fell through the trapdoor and into Serie B. Sport had a close shave in 2017, finishing 15th, and after a bright start which brought 5 wins in their first 10 matches, they faded badly. Despite, or perhaps due to, going through an astonishing four manager over the course of the season, Sport couldn’t find the reserves needed to close a gap that opened after taking only 6 points from a possible 51 between June and the end of September. A run of three straight wins at the end of October renewed hope of an unlikely escape, but despite beating Santos on the last day of the season, results elsewhere conspired to send them down.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: D-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Jair</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>18th - America-MG</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After winning the 2017 Serie B title, finishing two points ahead of the far more established and well resourced Internacional, hopes were high in the green and black third of Belo Horizonte that they could start to address the gap between themselves and their city rivals Cruzeiro and Atletico-MG. An opening day trouncing of Sport Recife proved to be a false dawn however, and a couple more wins in their next 5 matches was as good as it got. Hope persisted until an eleven match winless run beginning in September, and by the time a three point haul finally arrived again, at home against Santos in Round 35, the damage was done.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: D-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Matheusinho</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>19th - Vitoria</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vitoria were last season’s nearly men: nearly relegated and saved by the virtue of a +1 goal difference over Coritiba. That year they scored 50 goals and at least served up some entertainment for their fans. The same can’t be said for this year’s side who scored less than a goal a game on average, and conceded 63 times - by far the highest in the league this year. Unsurprisingly, they were on the wrong end of some of the biggest defeats of the season and finished six points from safety. They will hope to return to the top table at the first attempt, if only to resume their bitter rivalry with Bahia. </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: E</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Leo Gomes</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>20th - Parana</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might seem a little harsh to award an F to a team that was last in the top division in 2007, and who were only formed in 1989, but the fact is that the class of 2018 were dreadful for the vast majority of the campaign, and were relegated with six games left to play. With just four wins all season, and a pitiful 18 goals scored, it’s probably for the best that they have some time out of the spotlight to regroup and try to come back strong enough to average more than half a goal a game. Positives to take away? They had a better defensive record than Vitoria. They did the double over America-MG. What doesn’t kill you makes you stronger?</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: F</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Richard</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Season Review - Part One</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/season-review-part-one/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/season-review-part-one/</id>

        <updated>2018-12-17T15:00:57-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/23/Screen-Shot-2018-12-17-at-15.00.08.png" alt="Flamengo Fans at the Maracana" />
                    With the dust settled on the 62nd edition of the Campeonato Brasileirao, and the last pieces of green ticker tape cleared from the streets around Allianz Parque, it’s time to look back and assess the performance of the twenty teams who contested the most-watched and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/23/Screen-Shot-2018-12-17-at-15.00.08.png" alt="Flamengo Fans at the Maracana" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the dust settled on the 62nd edition of the Campeonato Brasileirao, and the last pieces of green ticker tape cleared from the streets around Allianz Parque, it’s time to look back and assess the performance of the twenty teams who contested the most-watched and richest national league outside of Europe. As with all modern football championships, there is an imbalance between the haves and have-nots, so while the the league table will certainly tell you who won the league, who will be contesting next year’s Libertadores and who will be checking Wikipedia to find out where the hell Operario Ferroviario Esporte Clube ply their trade (Ponta Grossa in Parana, in case you’re wondering), it doesn’t show you which teams achieved more than was expected of a ragtag bunch of journeymen and green-horned hopefuls, and which teams once again caused their fans to question why their side has less stamina for the race than an arthritic Shetland pony. Here’s our take on the teams who finished in the top half of the table.</span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>1st - Palmeiras</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It took until Round 37 for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Verdao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to confirm their record-extending tenth Brasileirao title, although from September on it looked unlikely that anyone would be able to stop Big Phil’s boys in green from claiming the crown. With a home record that reads P19 W16 D2 L1, including 13 straight wins between July and the end of the season and 22 games without suffering defeat, it’s not hard to see why last season’s runners up were worthy champions this time round. A wily old coach, a mean defence and the ability to get goals from all over the pitch (only striker Willian reached double figures) made this a very enjoyable season for <em>O</em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">s Porcos.</span></i></p>
<p><strong>Grade: A+</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Dudu</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>2nd - Flamengo</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Credit is due to Brazil’s most widely supported team for pushing Palmeiras all the way, but even the most dedicated fan of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Mengao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">must have sensed that it was not going to be their year long before Deyverson’s goal away at Vasco confirmed it. It seemed that for every misstep that Palmeiras took, Flamengo were right there behind them managing to find a banana skin all of their own. Still, this was a much better season than 2017 and credit must got to a squad that comfortably finished second despite having three managers in the calendar year. They will be hoping to go one better next year and end what will then be a ten-year wait for another title.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: A- </strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Cuellar</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>3rd - Internacional</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The season’s surprise package came in the form of last season’s Serie B runners up, although given Internacional’s pedigree it’s perhaps not a shock to see the side back where many fans believe they belong. Relegated for the first time in their history in 2016, they bounced straight back and, after a poor start in which they won only one of their opening five fixtures, continued bouncing up the table to become unlikely title contenders. In truth, it never looked like it was going to be the fairytale </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Nacao Vermelha </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">were dreaming of, and in the end they finished well behind the champions. Nevertheless, they will continue to enjoy their rehabilitation under coach Odair Hellmann as they enter next season’s Libertadores.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: A</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Victor Cuesta</strong></p>
<p><strong>4th - Gremio</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With their attention so focussed on the ultimately unsuccessful attempt to retain their Libertadores title, it’s not hard to imagine that had Gremio’s priorities lay in matters on the domestic front they might be basking in the glory of a first league title since 1996. A home record to rival Palmeiras was let down by flaky away form, but the team from Porto Alegre have enough about them to trouble any of the teams in the league.     </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: B</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Everton</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>5th - Sao Paulo</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And so to the arthritic Shetland pony of the introduction to this piece. First 19 games - W12 D5 L2; last 19 games - W4 D10 L5. ‘A game of two halves’ would be a kind way of describing a season which imploded when the team and their now departed journeyman manager, Diego Aguirre, got a serious case of vertigo when leading the league at the halfway point. Aguirre - manager of 14 teams in 16 years - left the team at the beginning of November but incoming head coach Andre Jardim could only steady the ship. Positives to be taken after a 13th place finish in 2017 for sure, but more heartache for fans who wonder when the glory days will return.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Diego Souza</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>6th - Atletico-MG</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Always an entertaining side to watch, Atletico-MG were involved in two of the most exciting games of the season - beating both Fluminese and Sport Recife 5-2 at the Estádio Raimundo Sampaio in Minas Gerais. A leaky defence featuring a 39-year old Leonardo Silva did them no favours, despite the heroics of goalkeeper Victor, and they will perhaps feel that an automatic Libertadores spot should have been theirs for the taking.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: B-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Ricardo Oliveira</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>7th - Atletico-PR</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another side who were able to improve their 2016 standing, and another that did so in some style. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Furacao </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">lived up to their nickname by delivering four of the biggest home wins of the season (5x1 vs. Chapecoense; 4x0 vs. Vitoria, America-MG and Sport Recife). The second half of the season saw 11 wins and went a long way to addressing a poor start. They even found time to lift their first Copa Sudamericana. Fans who delighted in their team’s attacking prowess this season, will no doubt be looking forward to climbing new heights in 2019.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: A</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Pablo</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>8th - Cruzeiro</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Back-to-back titles in 2013 and 2014 mean that expectations always run high in pre-season that Cruzeiro may mount another tilt at the title. A mid-season slump and a serious lack of firepower - they scored fewer goals than relegated Vitoria and Sport Recife - meant that this attempt never got off the ground, and they have a tight defence to thank for a Sudamericana spot they barely did enough to deserve.</span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Dede</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>9th - Botafogo</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since re-entering the top flight in 2016, Botafogo seem to have allayed fears that their 2014 relegation would lead to the historic side yo-yoing between leagues. Just three wins on the road all season however suggest that manager Ze Ricardo has a job on his hands to address one of the most porous defences outside of the relegated sides, and a team that lacks the self-belief to stand up to the ghosts of their illustrious past.    </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Igor Rabello</strong></p>
<br>
<p><strong>10th - Santos</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Where would Santos be without returning hero Gabriel Barbosa? Fans of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Peixe </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">will be thankful that it’s a question that they don’t have to answer, because even with the league’s top scorer they never looked like breaking into the Libertadores positions, never mind the elite G4. The sacking of Paulistao winning coach Dorival Junior in 2017 looks like a significant error as they cast around for an appropriate replacement. They will be hoping that Cuca, their third manager in 18 months, is that man. </span></p>
<p><strong>Grade: C-</strong></p>
<p><strong>Player of the Season: Gabriel Barbosa</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 38</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-38/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-38/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-12-03T22:39:31-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/22/IMG-20181126-WA0001.jpg" alt="Palmeiras Fans" />
                    With matters at the top of the table more-or-less resolved at the end of Round 37, the top three already set in stone come what may on the last day, attention turned to the scrabble to avoid the trapdoor to Serie B. With Vitoria and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/22/IMG-20181126-WA0001.jpg" alt="Palmeiras Fans" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With matters at the top of the table more-or-less resolved at the end of Round 37, the top three already set in stone come what may on the last day, attention turned to the scrabble to avoid the trapdoor to Serie B. With Vitoria and Parana already making plans for life outside the top flight, there were still six sides who went into the last round of games unsure of their status next season, all fighting to avoid being one of the other two </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">rebaixados.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perhaps the most high stakes encounter of the round was played out at the Maracana, as two sides still in the relegation mix faced off. Fluminese, the most storied of the at risk sides, made sure that the grand old stadium won’t suffer the somewhat dubious delights of second division football with a nervy 1-0 win over America-MG. Thing started well for the away side, and in the 27th minute they were rewarded for their hard work with a penalty after left-back Marlon brought down Aderlan. Luan, with just one goal to his name this season, stepped up to take it but found Julio Cesar equal to his attempt. The goal that secured Fluminese’s status, and ultimately condemned America-MG to return to the league they won last season, came fourteen minutes later courtesy of an excellent corner delivered by Marlon, more than making up for his earlier rash challenge. Richard made no mistake as he met the ball just outside the six-yard box, powering his header past Joao Ricardo. Ceara and Vasco da Gama were also both candidates for the drop and final day opponents, but with both sides knowing that a point would more than likely be enough it was little surprise that their tie ended 0-0. There was little to cheer for either set of fans, the sides mustering up just four shots on target between them, but everyone went home happy once events elsewhere confirmed that they will meet again next year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chapecoense and Sport Recife rounded out the group of six, with the former holding their fate in their own hands and the latter relying on the results of others to give them a chance of escape. Chapecoense faced a Sao Paulo side that have looked increasingly desperate for the season to end over the last few weeks, lest they fall any further from the lofty heights they commanded for so much of the season. They still had something to play for themselves, with the chance to move into fourth spot and automatic qualification for the Libertadores on the table, although the more conspiracy-minded fans of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Tricolor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> would have looked at the fixture list and suspected that Corinthians were unlikely to do them any favours in the attempt to better Gremio’s result when they played the fourth-placed side down in Rio Grande do Sul. As it was, the outcome of that match hardly mattered as Sao Paulo slumped to a 1-0 defeat and a season that promised so much became yet another one to forget. In the 68th minute, Leandro Pereira headed in the winning goal from a looped ball into the box, sparking scenes of delight in the crowd. This was followed by a nervous 25 minutes until the team that had just four days earlier commemorated the second anniversary of the tragic air disaster that robbed them of the most successful squad in their history could confirm their place in next season’s top division. Sport Recife faced Santos at home knowing that nothing short of a win would do. To their credit, they fulfilled their part of the requirement, beating their guests 2-1 following goals from Rogerio and Hernane, with Rodrygo pulling one back for Santos, however with the results in the round’s other ties not going their way all of their hard work counted for naught and they ultimately finished a point, and a more than a few hatfuls of goals, behind sixteenth-placed Vasco.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At Allianz Parque, the title celebrations were in full swing before kick-off and events on the pitch were of secondary importance to the trophy presentation after the match. As it was, the champions did what they have done all season and won at home, their only home loss of the season coming way back in May against Sport Recife, beating Vitoria 3-2. After taking a two goal lead, the hosts were pegged back by two goals in quick succession before Bruno Henrique put the icing on the championship-winning cake with a sweet strike from outside the area in the 90th minute. Those Sao Paulo fans who suspected that Corinthians wouldn’t exactly exert themselves in their match against Gremio will feel their suspicions were well placed as Jael headed in from close range after 12 minutes as Cassio flapped at a deflected shot. Corinthians supporters will surely point to their team’s poor form this season and the fact that they were playing a superior side as the reasons their side only managed one shot on and one shot off target in 90 minutes, although this is unlikely to change the minds of their aggrieved rival fans.      </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elsewhere, Parana managed to exit the stage with a semblance of pride, despite ending the season with just 23 points. A 1-1 draw with third-placed Internacional suggests that it might not be too long until the team from Curitiba make a return to the top flight. Two teams with nothing to play for and at least one eye on the beach before the state championships begin met in Salvador as Bahia played host to Cruzeiro. A game to forget ended 0-0 with the home side not even able to muster up the enthusiasm to get a shot on target. For reasons that aren’t quite clear, the last round of games did not all take place on Sunday. On Saturday night, Atletico-PR took a very creditable three point off Flamengo as they beat this year’s runners up 1-2 on their home turf. After falling behind to a 23rd minute Rholdolfo goal, second half strikes from Mateus Rossetto and Rony meant that the club from Parana end the season unbeaten in eight games. A degree of shine was taken off the achievement as Willian Arao of Flamengo and goal scorer Rony were both sent off late on. A poor challenge on the Atletico-PR forward earned Arao his second yellow before Rony reacted impetuously to provocation from Fernando Uribe by throwing out his shoulder at the striker. Also on Saturday night, Juan Cazares 18th minute goal meant that Atletico-MG beat Botafogo 1-0 and finished in sixth place, earning themselves a Libertadores playoff spot in the process.  </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Rounds 36 &amp; 37</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-rounds-36-and-37/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-rounds-36-and-37/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-27T07:28:18-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/21/Screen-Shot-2018-11-26-at-19.30.44.png" alt="Palmeiras Fans - 25/11/18" />
                    Palmeiras were crowned champions of the Brasileirao in a double game week where they claimed their 21st and 22nd victories of the season. The only thing to take a degree of shine off this moment for the team in green and white was the fact&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/21/Screen-Shot-2018-11-26-at-19.30.44.png" alt="Palmeiras Fans - 25/11/18" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras were crowned champions of the Brasileirao in a double game week where they claimed their 21st and 22nd victories of the season.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only thing to take a degree of shine off this moment for the team in green and white was the fact that their title win was confirmed in the environs of the Estadio Club de Regatas, rather than in front of their own fans, although many made the journey up to Rio in the hope of seeing their side confirm themselves as this year’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">campeoes. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">They were made to wait for their moment until the weekend despite sweeping aside America-MG 4-0 on Wednesday evening, as Flamengo gamely continued their ultimately fruitless attempt to haul in the leaders by beating Gremio 2-0. Sao Paulo had a golden opportunity on Thursday evening to leapfrog Gremio into fourth spot only to blow it by losing 2-0 away to Vasco da Gama. Internacional had also lost 1-2 at home to Atletico-MG the night before, so the status quo at the top was maintained for another round. Elsewhere on Wednesday, Santos and Botafogo drew 1-1, while Corinthians slipped to defeat 15 of the season, losing 1-0 away at Atletico-PR. On Thursday evening, Chapecoense earned vital points as they beat Sport Recife 2-1. Bahia took full points from Fluminese, winning 2-0, while Ceara eeked past Parana 1-0.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The penultimate round of the season kicked off in some style on Saturday evening as Santos hosted Atletico-MG. Uruguayan midfielder Carlos Santos got Santos off to a very quick start, scoring a fantastic free-kick after just 97 seconds. Not to be deterred, Atletico-MG struck back with a long range effort of their own, Ricardo Oliveria driving a low shot in off the post in the 17th minute. Seventeen minutes later and Santos were back in front: Felippe Cardoso finishing from close range after a give-and-go. Gabriel then got his 18th goal of the season in similar circumstances to put his team 3-1 ahead at the interval. Seven minutes after the break, the Santos defence had a moment to forget as goalkeeper Vanderlei managed to misjudge the flight of a corner allowing Ricardo Oliveira to grab his second of the game. Atletico-MG continued to press but to no avail, and Santos were able to hang on for maximum points despite having goal-scorer Carlos Santos dismissed in the 77th minute. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the pre-show entertainment over, all eyes turned to Sunday’s fixtures, and in particular Palmeiras’ visit to Vasco da Gama. Vasco, buoyed by their midweek win over Sao Paulo, were in no mood to make it easy for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Os Porcos</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and frustrated the visitors until midway through the second half. When it came, the goal that won the league was delivered from very close range. A long ball over the top of the Vasco defence was touched into the path of Deyverson who had the easiest of tasks to stroke home his ninth and most important goal of the season. With this win, it didn’t matter what happened in Flamengo’s game away at Cruzeiro, but the they secured second place with a 0-2 win - both goals coming from Everton Ribeiro and both worthy of winning a title rather than finishing runner up. The first was a smart finish from an acute angle after beating a couple of static Cruzeiro players; the second a wonderful strike from outside the area. The other two 5pm ties ended in draws: Vitoria and Gremio played out a 0-0, which meant that Sao Paulo were given another chance to go into the last round of games in fourth place if they could beat Sport Recife on Monday evening. The result was even less desirable for Vitoria as it confirmed that they will be joining Parana in Serie B next season. Atletico-PR and Ceara put on a much better show for the crowd as their match ended 2-2. Ceara went into half-time a goal to the good after Leandro Carvalho met a long ball over the top with a volley across Felipe Alves and into the bottom corner of the Atletico-PR net. The second half saw the home side draw level and then take the lead in the 58th minute - goals coming from Marcinho and Lucho Gonzalez - only for Ceara to restore parity when Wescley pick up on a poor clearance from Jose Ivaldo to slot the ball past Everson.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 7pm kick offs saw America-MG claim an absolutely vital win, one which ensured that their destiny will not be decided until the last day. Juninho’s 47th minute scuffed effort won’t win any goal of the season awards, but it might be the most important of the season for his team. Bahia then had centre-back Tiago Pagnussant sent off for a second bookable offence with three minutes left of regular time. Internacional cemented their third place finish as they beat Fluminese 2-0. Nicolas Lopez got both goals: the first, in the 75th minute, was a brilliant volley into the top corner from the edge of the Fluminese area following a headed clearance; the second, fourteen minutes later, was a much more routine affair as he reached Andres D’Alessandro’s through ball and finished calmly, placing the ball under the out-rushing Rodolfo. Corinthians’ dreadful season managed to muster up the strength to keep Chapecoense at bay for 90 minutes, although any meaningful attempts to score were few and far between and resulted in just one shot on goal for the home side. The point was enough to ensure that the reigning champions won’t suffer the ignominy of competing in the second division next season, but time must surely be running out for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">treinador </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jair Ventura. Chapecoense, meanwhile, have given themselves every chance of staying up when they host Sao Paulo next weekend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday evening saw Round 37 complete as Botafogo hosted Parana and Sao Paulo took on Sport Recife at the Morumbi stadium. There was little to play for but professional honour in Rio as Botafogo sat firmly in mid-table while Parana’s relegation was confirmed at the end of Round 32. In the end, they served up more entertainment that expected with two goals for Botafogo's Erik sandwiching a strike from Parana's Alex Santana. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sao Paulo still had fourth place and an automatic Libertadores spot firmly in their sights, and knew that a win against 18th placed Sport Recife would go a long way towards achieving that aim. Sport themselves had even more to play for as a win would take them up a place and level with Chapecoense in their battle to stay in the division. Neither side, therefore, will have been pleased with the point they took away from their stalemate. Sao Paulo now need to better Gremio's final day result, while Sport must hope for a win at home to Santos and for results elsewhere to go their way in order to maintain their position in the top flight. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">    </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>&quot;And the green and white upon my chest...&quot;</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Blair</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/and-the-green-and-white-upon-my-chest/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/and-the-green-and-white-upon-my-chest/</id>
            <category term="Sao Paulo"/>
            <category term="Santos"/>
            <category term="Palmeiras"/>
            <category term="Corinthians"/>
            <category term="Celtic"/>

        <updated>2018-11-26T19:27:53-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/20/IMG_0847.JPG" alt="" />
                    When I found out that I was moving to Sao Paulo the first thing I knew I had to research was the football teams at my disposal and pick one to start going to. A Celtic season ticket holder until I began travelling the world,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/20/IMG_0847.JPG" alt="" />
                <p>When I found out that I was moving to Sao Paulo the first thing I knew I had to research was the football teams at my disposal and pick one to start going to. A Celtic season ticket holder until I began travelling the world, I had gone eight years without really having a local team to call my own. In China I had been to a few Shanghai Shenhua games and had the chance to watch Nicholas Anelka play defensive midfield, something not many people have had the comic fortune to witness. In Slovakia I chose to play rather than attend games, so before coming to Brazil I was going to right a wrong and start following a team for real again. Sao Paulo is a city rich in football history and success so surely I was going to find a team to follow. In those years away from regular attendance something had certainly been missing. Yes, there is something fun about meeting up with a bunch of Glaswegians in a dingy Shanghai pub in the wee hours of the morning to watch a dodgy stream but something was always lacking. The sights and sounds of game day are things that make the game all the more enjoyable. The way to the stadium, the meeting of friends, the habitual pint in the same old pub (a war zone on an off day and a paradise of stale beer and pregame analysis on those halcyon afternoons). These were the things I’d been missing and was looking to find. But where?</p>
<p> Within a one-hour circumference of the city (make that 1-12 hours depending on the crazy traffic here) you can see four of the nation’s big teams: by the seaside, outside the city, you have home of Pele; Santos. As well as the Brazilian legend they can count Neymar and Rodrygo amongst their recent alumni and won the Libertadores in 2011. In the North of the city there is Palmeiras the most successful team in terms of Brasileirao championships; West is Sao Paulo FC who gave Kaka a start in the game and play their games in the 72,000 capacity Estadio Morumbi where the opening ceremony of the Copa America 2019 will be held; and to the East, Corinthians, the “team of the people” that conquered Chelsea in the 2012 FIFA World Club Cup competition. But who to support?</p>
<p> Picking a team isn’t something you really do as an adult. Most football fans will have had their team since a young age. Maybe family influenced, maybe the team of the day, maybe a moral or a style choice. Whatever the reason you will have chosen young and then stuck with it. For this reason I’ve seen some ups and some downs following Celtic through the 80s, 90s and beyond. The pleasure of those years was the emotional attachment; the sense of belonging. Going to a local “non-dom” primary school could be agonizing as Rangers waltzed to 9-in-a-row however the joy of winning the league in ’98 was magnified through the prism of that pain. Now, as a fully-grown adult, I was about to choose a team to cheer on in a language that I barely understood. Was it possible to find a team to share the same connection with?</p>
<p>A bit of research was in order and so I set about picking my Brazilian team. A simple scan of Google images got me on the right path. For someone with a deep-rooted love of my home club it may seem a bit facile to choose a team to support based on the colour of their strip but with only 20kg of luggage to haul with me it was handy when you could mix and match your kits! So, Palmeiras it was. Looking beyond the superficial, the decision actually made more sense. Both clubs founded by immigrants to represent a minority of society (Irish in Scotland and Italian in Brazil). Both clubs with passionate and vocal fans. Both are clubs with a history of playing attacking and exciting football. I’d found a new football home. But surely my passion couldn’t be the same as for the club I supported as a boy?</p>
<p> Well, three seasons down the line I can count myself as being on the way to being a Porco (the club nickname- a denigration of the Italian community embraced as a badge of honour by the fans). Of course it’s a work in progress. Slowly but surely I’m building up a friend group of fellow fans. Slowly learning the songs and feeling less like an outsider. Gradually feeling like I belong in this new family. And the Palmereise have helped this process of assimilation. If I ever turn up to a game in the hoops then invariably I will be stopped and asked about Celtic and why I’m here by people keen to share their love of Palmeiras. Nothing quite matches your first team but I feel I’ve made a good choice for my life in Brazil. Then again everything looks good through green and white tinted spectacles!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Rounds 34 &amp; 35</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-rounds-34-and-35/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-rounds-34-and-35/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-20T14:47:59-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/19/Screen-Shot-2018-11-19-at-18.56.03.png" alt="Palmeiras x Fluminese - 14/11/18" />
                    Round 34 took place midweek, and saw league leaders Palmeiras comfortably beat Fluminese 3-0. Internacional kept up the pressure with on the table toppers with a 2-0 victory over America-MG. Sao Paulo’s first match in the post-Diego Aguirre era ended in a 1-1 draw with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/19/Screen-Shot-2018-11-19-at-18.56.03.png" alt="Palmeiras x Fluminese - 14/11/18" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Round 34 took place midweek, and saw league leaders Palmeiras comfortably beat Fluminese 3-0. Internacional kept up the pressure with on the table toppers with a 2-0 victory over America-MG. Sao Paulo’s first match in the post-Diego Aguirre era ended in a 1-1 draw with Gremio, a result which further maintained the status quo at the top of the league. Parana couldn’t repeat the heroics of last weekend, but will heart from only losing 0-1 to Libertadores hopefuls Atletico-MG. Bahia’s 2-1 win over Ceara is probably enough to see them safe as they moved on to 44 points, meanwhile Sport and Vitoria would both have felt no better about their respective situations following their 0-0 draw. Corinthians fans must be longing for the end of the season as they had to endure yet another defeat, their 14th of the season, losing 1-0 away at Cruzeiro. Botafogo made it three wins on the spin, beating Chapecoense 0-1, and Flamengo won by the same scoreline at home against Santos to keep themselves in the race for the title. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Round 35, Palmeiras’ fortunate habit of timing their missteps to match those of their top of the table rivals continued on Sunday, as they could only manage a draw away at Serie B-bound Parana, a blow to their title ambitions that was softened considerably by the news which filtered into the stadium that second placed Internacional had lost away at mid-table also-rans Botafogo. It was Parana who took the lead in the 35th minute of a rain-swept encounter: Keslley poking a low cross past a sprawling Weverton. Parana are experiencing something of a post-relegation bounce, given their woeful form for most of this season, but they were not able to keep Palmeiras completely at bay here and early in the second half they gave away a penalty after Willian’s goal-bound shot was handled in the area. There were to be no more goals under the grey Londrina sky, but a point against this season’s likely league champions will have felt like a victory for the home team. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over in Rio de Janiero, Internacional did their best to ensure that Palmeiras could sleep easy, slumping to a 0-1 loss against Botafogo following Erik’s smart 42nd minute finish; the right-sided winger bringing the ball under control with his chest, wrong-footing Zeca in the process, before slamming the ball home. Things did not improve for the away side in the second half, and the bad became farcical in injury-time as first Wellington Silva then Rodrigo Moledo were dismissed. Silva received a straight red for retaliation following a heavy tackle from behind by Rodrigo Pimpao, while Moledo can feel himself fortunate to have got away with a second yellow card after he pushed the referee when his penalty appeals were turned down.      </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the top two faltered, Flamengo grasped the opportunity to move into second place with a tight 0-1 victory over Sport Recife. Despite having Lucas Paqueta sent off for a second bookable offence in the 61st minute, Flamengo kept the pressure up and were rewarded for their endeavour when Willian Arao beat his marker just inside the 6-yard box to head past Mailson. In the battle for the fourth automatic Libertadores spot, both Gremio and Sao Paulo took maximum points in their home ties against Chapecoense and Cruzeiro respectively. Cicero met a high ball into the box to put Gremio one up after 24 minutes, with Everton beating Jandrei to a defence-splitting pass and lifting the ball over the goalkeeper to make it 2-0 in the 75th minute. Sao Paulo’s caretaker-manager, Andre Jardine, has the first win of his attempt to stake a claim to the job full-time. Diego Souza got the decisive goal, finishing acrobatically after Nene’s corner was headed into the ground by Robert Arboleda.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sunday also saw America-MG clinch a crucial win at the other end of the table, beating Santos 2-1 with goals from Rafael Moura and Matheusinho either side of the 17th goal of the season for the league’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">melhor marcador</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Gabriel. The win moved America-MG up two places to 17th, and within touching distance of safety. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Saturday evening, Corinthians overcame a determined Vasco da Gama side 1-0 after Mateus Vital headed powerfully past Fernando Miguel from Fagner’s high hanging cross. A late Neilton penalty wasn’t enough to save Vitoria from defeat against Atletico-PR, and things are looking bleak for the team from Bahia as they are now winless in six and have a significantly worse goal difference than the other teams in the relegation zone. It was a bad day all round for the home side. Atletico-PR’s opening goal was gifted to them as Ramon got himself into a mix and ended up putting the ball in his own net after Marcelo Cirino’s header was palmed onto the post by Vitoria keeper, Joao Gabriel. They were also reduced to ten-men in the 89th minute when Jeferson received his second yellow card of the match. In Belo Horizonte, Bahia left disappointed that they could not make numbers count as they lost 1-0 to an Atletico-MG side who had Fabio Santos sent off in the 53rd minute. Just two minutes earlier, Juan Cazares had given Atletico-MG the lead with what turned out to be the winning goal, setting himself up for a wonderful half-volley from the edge of the Bahia box following Yimmi Chara’s cutback.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday evening saw two out-of-form teams in the shape of Fluminese and Ceara battling to keep themselves clear of the drop zone. A draw was always the most likely result, and so it proved to be with both teams failing to find a way through in a game of few chances. With three matches left to play, neither side will be taking anything for granted, but a point and a clean sheet was a satisfactory outcome for all involved. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 33</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-33/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-33/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-12T09:09:42-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/18/DSC02906.JPG" alt="Itaquera - Arena Corinthians" />
                    Palmeiras’ seemingly inexorable march to the title faltered slightly on Sunday evening as they could only manage a draw away at an out-of-sorts Atletico-MG. A well worked move down the left was finished in spectacular style by Elias as he teed himself up to volley&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/18/DSC02906.JPG" alt="Itaquera - Arena Corinthians" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras’ seemingly inexorable march to the title faltered slightly on Sunday evening as they could only manage a draw away at an out-of-sorts Atletico-MG. A well worked move down the left was finished in spectacular style by Elias as he teed himself up to volley the ball into the top corner past a helpless Weverton, giving Atletico-MG the lead just under half-way through the second half. It took a good save from the Palmeiras goalkeeper to stop Luan making it two just minutes later, as he found space in the area after a give-and-go with Fabio Santos and unleashed a stinging low shot. It was Palmeiras, however, who got a rub of the green as they were awarded a soft penalty after Adilson was adjudged to have pulled back Edu Dracena in the 77th minute. Bruno Henrique duly scored a perfectly placed penalty, sending Victor the wrong way and the ball into the bottom right-hand corner, ensuring that that his team took another step towards the title. This step was made all the more comfortable by the news that in the north-east of the country Internacional were unable to capitalise on an early lead against Ceara, ending up with a 1-1 draw of their own. Leandro Damiao’s sixth goal in six games, finishing after Everson had blocked his initial shot, gave Palmeiras’ closest rivals the lead, before Ricardinho levelled matters in the 42nd minute, converting a low cross from close range. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Estadio Manoel Barradas played host to the weekend’s third derby, following Saturday’s ties, as Vitoria and Bahia played their roles in an entertaining 2-2 draw. The hosts Vitoria were twice pegged back as they went in search of a vital win and a chance to move out of the relegation zone. Bahia are much more comfortably placed in mid-table, six points above trouble, and this will certainly feel like two-points lost for Paulo Carpegiani’s struggling team. In Porto Alegre, Gremio snatched a win thanks to Matheus Henrique’s 95th minute goal. Thiago Galhardo finished off a break-away move to put Vasco in front on 12 minutes, only for Jael to equalise eight minutes later, heading in unmarked at the far post. Seventy five goalless minutes then followed until Matheus Henrique’s decisive contribution: an ambitious long range shot, which should have been dealt with easily but instead was fumbled into the net by Vasco’s Uruguayan #1, Martin Silva. Sunday’s action was rounded off by Sport Recife’s visit to Rio to meet Fluminese. Sport have enjoyed a great run of form in recent weeks, winning four of their last five, and will have arrived at the Maracana hopeful of another good result as they faced a side who have lost their last two without scoring. A goalless first half was followed by a scoreless second, however, and both teams had to settle for a point, a result which kept Sport Recife out of the bottom four, at least until Chapecoense play on Monday evening. Fluminese came closest to breaking the deadlock, and had the ball in the net late on after Luciano’s close-range finish, only for the assistant referee to flag it up as offside.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s match-ups saw derby action in both Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro as Flamengo visited Botafogo and Corinthians hosted city rivals Sao Paulo. Given their poor run of form recently, Corinthians gave a good account of themselves, holding Diego Aguirre’s team to a 1-1 draw despite going down to ten men shortly before the interval. Chilean midfielder Angelo Araos was sent-off for a second bookable offence when he hit out after a coming together with Reinaldo. In fact it was Corinthians who took the lead, Ralf on target with a low drive from distance after 72 minutes, but Sao Paulo finally made their numbers count as Brenner equalised nine minutes later, directing Nene’s goalbound shot past Cassio. Up the coast in Rio, Botafogo earned an important three points in a bad tempered 2-1 victory. Ten yellow cards were shown as goals from Erik and Leonardo Valencia earned the points for the team in black and white. Vitinho nodded in a reply for Flamengo early in the second half, but Botafogo did enough to hang on for the win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s other matches were similarly marked by ill-discipline. Both sides ended the match with ten men as already-relegated Parana visited America-MG. Parana’s Rene was the first to see red before Messias was also sent marching in the 86th minute. The match is likely to be remembered for more positive reasons however, by half of those concerned at least, as a 0-1 win for Parana ended a winless streak stretching all the way back to July. Atletico-PR and Cruzeiro went one better than the Rio derby as eleven players were booked in their encounter. Marcelo Cirino and Raphael Veiga’s first half goals were enough to secure the points for Atletico-PR, a win which lifted them into 6th place and the Libertadores qualifying round spots.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monday night football was provided by Chapecoense’s visit to Santos, as the away team looked to leapfrog their relegation rivals into 16th place.  </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Brasileirao - Round 32</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul McDaniel</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-32/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/brasileirao-round-32/</id>
            <category term="Brasileirão"/>

        <updated>2018-11-06T07:16:48-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/17/Screen-Shot-2018-11-06-at-07.15.48.png" alt="Palmeiras fans at Allianz Parque" />
                    Palmeiras took a huge stride towards securing the title on Saturday evening as they came out on top in an exciting 3-2 win over Santos. This looked to be a tricky tie for the leaders, with Santos on a good run of form and the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/17/Screen-Shot-2018-11-06-at-07.15.48.png" alt="Palmeiras fans at Allianz Parque" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmeiras took a huge stride towards securing the title on Saturday evening as they came out on top in an exciting 3-2 win over Santos. This looked to be a tricky tie for the leaders, with Santos on a good run of form and the team in green still nursing a potential hangover after their midweek semi-final exit from the Copa Libertadores at the hands of Boca Juniors. If they were feeling tired after their exertions against the Argentines, they showed no sign in the first half as they went into the interval two goals to the good, courtesy of Dudu and Edu Dracena. With the game very much in their grasp, things took a turn when Jonathan Copete clawed one back for Santos on 55 minutes. Ten minutes later and it was game on as Dodo levelled for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Peixe. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The lead was not to last, however, as Vitor Luis grabbed the winning goal from a free-kick in the 71st minute. There was still time for more drama as Santos’ Diego Pituca picked up a second yellow card and was dismissed ten minutes from time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saturday’s other games were not quite so dramatic. Gremio and Vasco da Gama both winning 0-1 away at Atletico-MG and Fluminese respectively. Pedro Geromel struck early for Gremio, while Maxi Lopez’s fine run of form continued with his fifth goal in his last six games. Atletico-MG had Ecuador midfield Junior Sornoza dismissed deep into injury time to compound the loss.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sunday afternoon saw fourth host second as Sao Paulo welcomed Flamengo to the Morumbi. Like Saturday’s main attraction, this clash between two of this season’s title contenders didn’t disappoint with four goals and leads won and lost. Diego Souza opened the scoring for Sao Paulo with his eleventh goal of the season, only for the hosts to be pegged back two minutes later as Fernando Uribe netted an equaliser in the tenth minute. After the break, Helio Junio must have though he’d done enough to secure all three points for Sao Paulo, only for Rodinei to score in the 80th minute and draw the team from Rio level once again. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other big game on Saturday took place in Porto Alegre as Internacional faced Atletico-PR. A win would move the home team up to second place, but for most of the match it looked like it would be another missed opportunity for Odair Hellmann’s team as Camancho scored for Atletico-PR in the 62nd minute. Rodrigo Moledo equalised in the 82nd minute, and it looked like Internacional would have to settle for a point, but they were awarded a 94th minute penalty, which was duly converted by Andres D’Alessandro. His team are now just five points behind Palmeiras with six games left to play. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elsewhere, Parana and Vitoria played out a 1-1 draw, which did neither side any favours in their battle against the drop, but did halt a run of four successive losses for the league’s bottom side. Parana are now winless in 18 games, and Serie B bound barring a miracle involving a run of six successive wins and a serious goal difference overhaul. America-MG also remain in imminent danger of the drop as they failed to pick up any points at home to Cruzeiro, losing 1-2 on the night.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Remarkably, last season’s champions Corinthians are still not out of danger and a couple more results like Sunday evening’s loss to Botafogo may well see </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">O Timao</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sweating over results elsewhere. Rodrigo Lindoso scored the only goal of the game for the hosts, a result which pulled Botafogo further clear of the relegation zone. Bahia condemned Chapecoense to defeat by the same scoreline, Elber getting the vital goal and helping his team to the relative comfort of 11th place while leaving Chapecoense firmly in the drop zone.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday evening, Sport Recife continued their recent renaissance with a narrow win over fellow strugglers Ceara. Gabriel scored the all important goal in the 53rd minute, helping his side to their fourth win in the last five games and, most importantly, lifting them out of the bottom four.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Away Daze</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Hardwicke</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://futebolbrazil.com/an-away-daze/"/>
        <id>https://futebolbrazil.com/an-away-daze/</id>
            <category term="Sao Paulo"/>
            <category term="Juventus"/>
            <category term="Copa Paulista"/>
            <category term="Away Days"/>

        <updated>2018-11-05T22:44:59-02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/16/PHOTO-2018-11-05-13-09-35.jpg" alt="" />
                    It’s 8 am on a Sunday morning and the sun is shining brightly on the crowd outside the ‘Onion bar’ in Mooca, a barrio in the Central-West district of Sao Paulo. The Onion is home to Sector 2, a group of C.A. Juventus fans who&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://futebolbrazil.com/media/posts/16/PHOTO-2018-11-05-13-09-35.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s 8 am on a Sunday morning and the sun is shining brightly on the crowd outside the ‘Onion bar’ in Mooca, a barrio in the Central-West district of Sao Paulo. The Onion is home to Sector 2, a group of C.A. Juventus fans who have welcomed me with open arms since I first found my way to a Juve game around a year ago. A group of around 40 or so fans have gathered here to take the two-hour bus ride North to Atibaia, a conurbation of around 125,000 people, for an important game in the Copa Paulista (a tournament for sides in the state of Sao Paulo who are not part of the national set-up).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Away games for Juventus are usually within city limits (and reachable by public transport) or several hundred kilometres away.  As a result, bus trips such as these are somewhat rare and excitement levels are high: many of the beers marked for consumption en route have already disappeared and large glasses of industrial-flavoured cachaca are doing the rounds. Everyone is in high spirits. But weren’t we supposed to be leaving already? The bus driver seems to be the only one keen to get going. Eventually, more beers and ice arrive, the big bass drum is loaded onto the bus and we are on our way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The party starts immediately and for a Sunday morning I must say it is a sight, and sound, to behold.  For the duration of the journey, the seats are treated like the terraces at Rua Javari, Juventus’ home, as the group bounce and sway through a repertoire of songs seemingly aimed at insulting every other club in Sao Paulo one after the other.  Moving slowly through the notorious city traffic, the bus is greeted with no shortage of honks, cheers and waves from passers-by. Heavy smoke fills the air, thankfully masking the smell from the toilet (passengers who force their way through the throng are urged not to flush for fear of making it worse), the drum beat pounds away and as we make our way into the countryside, light fittings and luggage racks begin to fall from the ceiling, much to the amusement of those underneath. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we approach Atibaia, I check the time on my phone and am alarmed to note that kick-off time was 15 minutes ago! I turn to inform Joao, stood next to me, but he simply beams at me as he puts his arm around my shoulder: ‘Yes we are missing the game,’ he chuckles, ‘but we knew this would happen before we left The Onion.’ It takes me a few moments to process this. I glance around at the swaying, smiling, care-free faces in front of me and am reminded of a familiar feeling I have experienced many times before in situations such as these: sure, the game is important, but there is something more powerful here, a togetherness, a bond formed by the collective expression of emotion that occurs when passionate people gather together over something they love. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel this sensation once more when, after the game, I remark to Fernando, one of the leaders of Sector 2, how well Juventus played today. “Yeah?” he replies, looking vaguely pleased with this suggestion, for he has no idea what happened on the pitch. Like others around him, his match was spent facing his fellow supporters, bouncing up and down, arms pumping rhythmically in time with the chanting. Expressing his love for the beautiful game.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
